我有一阵子没开记者会了
Been a while since I was up here in front of you.
我猜我只好照着提词卡念吧
Maybe I'll do us all a favour and just stick to the cards.
有传闻说我涉及了一些事件
There's been speculation that I was involved in the events that occurred
发生在公路和屋顶发生的事…
on the freeway and the rooftop...
抱歉 你真的以为我们会相信
Sorry, Mr Stark, do you honestly expect us to believe that
一名穿着钢铁盔甲的保镖刚好出现
that was a bodyguard in a suit that conveniently appeared,
况且你平常很讨厌带保镖
despite the fact that you sorely despise bodyguards?
对
Yes.
而且这名神秘保镖居然配有…
And this mysterious bodyguard was somehow equipped
斯塔克工业最先进的高机密武器
with an undisclosed Stark high-tech powered battle...
（莫斯科）
我知道这令人费解
I know that it's confusing.
但质疑官方说法是一回事 而另一回事
It is one thing to question the official story, and another thing entirely
又是胡乱地谴责 瞎猜我是超级英雄…
to make wild accusations, or insinuate that I'm a superhero.
老实说 我不是当英雄的料
I mean, let's face it, I'm not the heroic type.
我的人格有很多缺陷
A laundry list of character defects,
而且也公开做过许多蠢事
all the mistakes I've made, largely public.
事实是…
The truth is
我就是钢铁侠
I am Iron Man.
伊万…
Ivan.
万尼亚
Vanya.
那应该是你
别听他们胡说八道
对不起
我只能给你我的知识
“斯塔克工业”
“方舟反应炉”
“安东・万科 霍华德・斯塔克”
“托尼是钢铁侠”
“斯塔克的方舟反应炉”
“托尼・斯塔克：我是钢铁侠”
“时代杂志年度风云人物”
“钢铁侠稳定东西关系”
风速30里 高度1万5千尺
270 at 30 knots. Holding steady at 15,000 feet.
你现在可以进入降落区
You are clear for exfiltration over the drop zone.
（6个月后）
（斯塔克博览会 纽约法拉盛）
托尼！托尼！托尼！托尼！
Tony! Tony! Tony! Tony!
回来真好！
It's good to be back.
-你们很想我？ -炸掉什么吧！
-You missed me? -Blow something up!
我也想你们 炸掉什么？我干过了呀！
I missed you, too. Blow something up? I already did that.
我没有说全球沉浸于…
I'm not saying that the world is enjoying
多年长期持续的和平状态是因为我
its longest period of uninterrupted peace in years because of me.
我也没说世上没人像我一样
I'm not saying that from the ashes of captivity,
如同浴火凤凰般重获新生
never has a greater phoenix metaphor been personified in human history.
我更没说过“山姆大叔”能舒服地躺在椅子上
I'm not saying that Uncle Sam can kick back on a lawn chair,
悠闲地喝着冰茶
sipping on an iced tea
因为我始终保持巅峰状态
because I haven't come across anyone who's man enough
没人敢跟我单挑！
to go toe-to-toe with me on my best day.
我爱你 钢铁侠！
I love you, Tony!
拜托 我不重要
Please, it's not about me.
你们也不重要
It's not about you.
我们都不重要 重要的是传承
It's not even about us. It's about legacy.
我们该替未来世代留下什么
It's about what we choose to leave behind for future generations.
所以从明年开始 自1974年以来的第一次
And that's why for the next year and for the first time since 1974,
最优秀的人才
the best and brightest men and women
来自全世界不同国家和公司…
of nations and corporations the world over
将提供他们的资源 分享他们的共同远见
will pool their resources, share their collective vision,
创造一个更美好的未来
to leave behind a brighter future.
我们并不重要
It's not about us.
因此 我想说的是
Therefore, what I'm saying, if I'm saying anything,
欢迎参观斯塔克工业博览会
is welcome back to the Stark Expo.
有位特别嘉宾将从前世回来
And now, making a special guest appearance
向你们说明这一切
from the great beyond to tell you what it's all about,
请欢迎我父亲 霍华德
please welcome my father, Howard.
科技能达成一切
Everything is achievable through technology.
更美好的生活、更健康的身体
Better living, robust health,
这是人类历史上第一次能达成世界和平的可能
and for the first time in human history, the possibility of world peace.
我谨代表斯塔克工业
So, from all of us here at Stark lndustries,
向各位介绍未来的城市
I would like to personally introduce you to the City of the Future.
科技让人类充满无限的可能
Technology holds infinite possibilities for mankind,
“血液毒性：19%"
and will one day rid society of all its ills.
科技将很快改变你的日常生活
Soon, technology will affect the way you live your life every day.
不必再辛苦工作
No more tedious work,
空出时闲进行休闲活动并且享受美好生活
leaving more time for leisure activities and enjoying the sweet life.
欢迎参观斯塔克工业博览会
The Stark Expo. Welcome.
记者在斯塔克工业博览会连线报导
We are coming to you live from the kickoff of the Stark Expo,
托尼・斯塔克刚刚走下舞台
where Tony Stark has just walked offstage.
各位今晚不能来没关系
Don't worry if you can't make it down here tonight
因为博览会将持续举行一整年
because this Expo goes on all year long.
我会参观来自世界各地
And I'm gonna be here checking out all the attractions
不同的设施、摊位和发明
and the pavilions and the inventions from all around the world.
-一定要加入我… -外面一片混乱 小心点
-Make sure you join me... -All right, it's a zoo out there, watch out.
-开门 我们走吧 -大家好
-Open up, let's go. -Hey! Nice to see you.
-谢了 我记得你 -托尼 托尼…
-All right. Thank you. I remember you. -Tony, Tony...
-打给我 -嘿 嘿 够了 够了
-Call me. -Hey, hey, hey, hey. Come on, come on.
你好 我的荣幸
Hello. It would be a pleasure.
-好的 -再见了 小鬼
-Okay. -See you, buddy.
这是赖瑞
This is Larry.
甲骨文的创办人 幸会了
Hey, the oracle of Oracle. What a pleasure.
-很高兴认识你 -再打给我
-Nice to see you. -Call me. Call me.
-赖瑞・金  -赖瑞！
-Larry King. -Larry!
棒呆了 我的粉丝
Yes, my people, my people.
终于出来了
Come on, Tony. There we go.
-他们还算很冷静嘛 -不算太糟
-Very mellow. -That wasn't so bad.
超完美的
No, it was perfect.
你看 全新车款
Look what we got here, the new model.
-她是随车附赠的吗？  -希望是喔
-Hey, does she come with the car? -I certainly hope so.
-你是谁？ -执法官
-And you are? -Marshal.
-爱尔兰妞 我喜欢 -幸会了 托尼
-Irish. I like it. -Pleased to meet you, Tony.
我来开车 行吗？ 你打哪来的？
I'm on the wheel. Do you mind? Where you from?
-贝德福 -你来这里干嘛？
-Bedford. -What are you doing here?
-我来找你 -是吗？你找我
-Looking for you. -Yeah? You found me.
-你找我干嘛？ -递传票给你
-What are you up to later? -Serving subpoenas.
他不喜欢别人给他东西
He doesn't like to be handed things.
-这是我的怪癖 -拿给我
-Yeah, I have a peeve. -I got it.
你被勒令
You are hereby ordered
出席参议院军事委员会
to appear before the Senate Armed Services Committee
时间是在明早九点整
tomorrow morning at 9:00 a.m.
-我能看你的警徽吗？  -他要看警徽
-Can I see a badge? -You wanna see the badge?
他特别喜欢警徽
He likes the badge.
-你还是喜欢吗？  -对
-You still like it? -Yep.
-我们离华盛顿有多远？ -华盛顿？250英里
-How far are we from D.C.? -D.C.? 250 miles.
（华盛顿）
斯塔克先生 我们继续刚才的议题好吗？斯塔克先生 拜托
Mr Stark, could we pick up now where we left off? Mr Stark. Please.
-是的 亲爱的？ -能专心听我的话吗？
-Yes, dear? -Can I have your attention?
没问题
Absolutely.
你是否拥有一种特殊武器？
Do you or do you not possess a specialised weapon?
-我没有 我没有 -你没有？
-I do not. I do not. -You do not?
这要看你认为什么才算武器
Well, it depends on how you define the word "weapon."
-钢铁侠就算武器 -我的发明并不算武器
-The Iron Man weapon. -My device does not fit that description.
那你会怎么形容它？
Well... How would you describe it?
它是什么就是什么 参议员
I would describe it by defining it as what it is, Senator.
-它是什么？ -它是一种高科技的假肢
-As? -It's a high-tech prosthesis.
那是…那是…我那是想得到最好的形容词
That is... That is...That's actually the most apt description Ican make of it.
它是一种武器 它是武器
It's a weapon. It's a weapon, Mr Stark.
如果你是以人民福祉为优先…
Please, if your priority was actually the well-being of the American citizen...
不 我是以把钢铁侠这项武器
My priority is to get the Iron Man weapon turned over to the people
-交给美国人民为优先 -想都别想
-of the United States of America. -Well, you can forget it.
我就是钢铁侠 我和钢铁盔甲合为一体
I am Iron Man. The suit and I are one.
交出钢铁侠就是交出我自己
To turn over the Iron Man suit would be to turn over myself,
那算是劳役或是卖淫…
which is tantamount to indentured servitude or prostitution,
要看你是在哪一州
depending on what state you're in.
-我不能给你 -听好 我不是专家…
-You can't have it. -Look, I'm no expert...
卖淫专家？当然不是 你是参议员 好吧
ln prostitution? Of course not. You're a senator. Come on.
我并不是武器专家
I'm no expert in weapons.
但是我们请来一位武器专家
We have somebody here who is an expert on weapons.
我要传唤贾斯汀・汉默 国防部目前主要的军火商
I'd now like to call Justin Hammer, our current primary weapons contractor.
请记录我看见汉默先生走进来
Let the record reflect that I observed Mr Hammer entering the chamber,
并且我想
and I am wondering
但我并没看见任何武器专家
if and when any actual expert will also be in attendance.
没错 我并不是专家 你才是 托尼
Absolutely. I'm no expert. I defer to you, Anthony.
你才是个天才
You're the wonder boy.
参议员 请容我发言
Senator, if I may.
或许我并不是专家 但你知道谁才是真的专家？
I may well not be an expert, but you know who was the expert?
你父亲！霍华德・斯塔克
Your dad. Howard Stark.
他不但是我们的大家长 更是军事工业之父
Really a father to us all, and to the military-industrial age.
但是请搞清楚 他不是卖花儿童 他是只雄狮
Let's just be clear. He was no flower child. He was a lion.
我们都知道为什么来这里 这半年来
We all know why we're here. ln the last six months,
托尼・斯塔克打造了一把犀利宝剑
Anthony Stark has created a sword with untold possibilities.
他却坚持那只是一面盾牌
And yet he insists it's a shield.
它要我们信任他 要我们躲在他后面
He asks us to trust him as we cower behind it.
我真希望我觉得很安全 我是真的这么希望
I wish I were comforted, Anthony, I really do.
我很希望出门时不必锁门
I'd love to leave my door unlocked when I leave the house,
但这里不是加拿大
but this ain't Canada.
我们活在充满危险的世界
You know, we live in a world of grave threats,
斯塔克先生不一定能预知的危险
threats that Mr Stark will not always be able to foresee.
谢谢各位
Thank you.
天佑钢铁侠 天佑美国
God bless Iron Man. God bless America.
说得好 汉默先生
That is well said, Mr Hammer.
现在我们要邀请…
The committee would now like to invite
詹姆斯・罗德中校出席会议
Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes to the chamber.
洛德？
Rhodey? What?
兄弟 没想到你会来
Hey, buddy. I didn't expect to see you here.
是我 我来了 接受事实 继续吧
Look, it's me, I'm here. Deal with it. Let's move on.
我只是…
I just...
-别说了 -好吧 我不说了
-Drop it. -All right, I'll drop it.
这是罗德中校收集到…
I have before me a complete report on the Iron Man weapon,
有关钢铁侠武器的完整报告
compiled by Colonel Rhodes. And, Colonel, for the record,
中校 请你念57页第4段
can you please read page 57, paragraph four?
你要我念特定的段落
You're requesting that I read specific selections
-是报告中的 议员？ -是的
-from my report, Senator? -Yes, sir.
我以为我是来做…
It was my understanding that I was going to be testifying
完整及详细的报告
in a much more comprehensive and detailed manner.
我了解 但是今天有很多变数
l understand. A lot of things have changed today.
-假如你能读一下… -你懂的
-So if you could just read... -You do understand
光是念出那一个段落不能代表…
that reading a single paragraph out of context does not reflect
-我的完整报告…  -请你念出来 中校 我懂 谢谢
-the summary of my final... -Just read it, Colonel. I do. Thank you.
好吧
Very well.
“由于钢铁侠并不隶属政府任何单位
"As he does not operate within any definable branch of government,
钢铁侠具有潜在的安全隐患 对于国家
"Iron Man presents a potential threat to the security of both the nation
以及国家的利益来说”
"and to her interests."
但是我的结论是…
I did, however, go on to summarise
钢铁侠的好处远比坏处更多
that the benefits of Iron Man far outweigh the liabilities.
-并且符合我们利益的是…  -够了 中校
-And that it would be in our interest... -That's enough, Colonel.
-让斯塔克先生… -我说够了
-...to fold Mr Stark... -That's enough.
…加入军事指挥体系 议员
...into the existing chain of command, Senator.
我不喜欢加入任何体系 但我倒是可以考虑当国防部长
I'm not a joiner, but I'll consider Secretary of Defense, if you ask nice.
我可以减少工作时数
We can amend the hours a little bit.
如果可能 我还想继续播放
I'd like to go on and show, if I may,
你报告中的影像
the imagery that's connected to your report.
我认为目前还不是…
I believe it is somewhat premature to reveal these images
-向大众公开这些影像的时候 -恕我直言
-to the general public at this time. -With all due respect,
我能理解 中校
Colonel, I understand.
但如果你能描述这些影像 我们会非常感激
And if you could just narrate those for us, we'd be very grateful.
把影像调出来
Let's have the images.
情报显示这些影像中的装置
Intelligence suggests that the devices seen in these photos
其实是斯塔克先生钢铁盔甲的仿冒品
are, in fact, attempts at making manned copies of Mr Stark's suit.
这一点经过我们的盟国以及地面情报单位的证实
This has been corroborated by our allies and local intelligence on the ground,
这些钢铁盔甲目前很可能可以使用
indicating that these suits are quite possibly, at this moment, operational.
等一下 给我看看 有东西了
Hold on one second, buddy. Let me see something here.
我真厉害 我控制了你的屏幕
Boy, I'm good. I commandeered your screens.
我需要它们 该让这一切透明化了
I need them. Time for a little transparency.
-我们看看这到底是怎么回事 -他在做什么？
-Now, let's see what's really going on. -What is he doing?
请你们看电脑屏幕
If you will direct your attention to said screens...
我相信那是北韩
l believe that's North Korea.
能不能关掉？快关掉
Can you turn that off? Take it off.
伊朗
Iran.
没有紧急严重的威胁 那是贾斯汀・汉默吗？
No grave immediate threat here. Is that Justin Hammer?
他怎么也在搞仿冒品？
How did Hammer get in the game?
贾斯汀 你上电视了 焦点人物
Justin, you're on TV. Focus up.
很好 向左转 很好 向右转
Okay, give me a left twist. Left's good. Turn to the right.
糟了 糟了！
Oh, shit. Oh, shit!
大部份的国家得花5到10年
Yeah, I'd say most countries, five, 10 years away.
汉默工业至少要花20年
Hammer Industries, 20.
容我指出那位驾驶员没有死
I'd like to point out that that test pilot survived.
我想我们看够了 他证明了他的看法
I think we're done, is the point that he's making.
-我觉得没有任何理由… -我猜我只能说：不客气
-I don't think there's any reason... -The point is, you're welcome, I guess.
-什么意思？ -我能防止核战的恫吓
-For what? -Because I'm your nuclear deterrent.
钢铁侠很有用 我们很安全 美国很安全
It's working. We're safe. America is secure.
你要我的产品？想都别想！
You want my property? You can't have it.
不过我帮了你们个大忙
But I did you a big favour.
我一个人就能维持世界和平
I've successfully privatized world peace.
你还想要我怎样？现在就是这样！
What more do you want? For now!
我试着和那些跳梁小丑合作
I tried to play ball with these ass-clowns.
…去你的 斯塔克先生
...you, Mr Stark. ...you, buddy.
散会 今天散会
We're adjourned. We're adjourned for today.
-好吧 -你真是个开心果
-Okay. -You've been a delight.
听好 我全是为了人民
My bond is with the people.
我以自己的乐趣为国家服务
And I will serve this great nation at the pleasure of myself.
如果我向全世界证明了什么
If there's one thing I've proven
那就是你们绝对能信赖我…能让自己很高兴
it's that you can count on me to pleasure myself.
（加州马里布）
醒醒吧 老爹回来了
Wake up. Daddy's home.
欢迎回家
Welcome home, sir.
恭喜博览会开幕仪式
Congratulations on the opening ceremonies.
以及参议院听证会大大地成功
They were such a success, as was your Senate hearing.
容我说一句
And may I say how refreshing it is
你穿着衣服上电视令人耳目一新
to finally see you in a video with your clothing on, sir.
你！
You!
我发誓我会把你拆掉 我会泡烂你的主板
I swear to God I'll dismantle you. I'll soak your motherboard.
我会把你做成书架
I'll turn you into a wine rack.
这种臭东西我还要喝多少？
How many ounces a day of this gobbledegook am I supposed to drink?
80盎斯才能消除钯中毒的征状
We are up to 80 ounces a day to counteract the symptoms, sir.
检查钯元素含量
Check palladium levels.
血液毒性：24%
Blood toxicity, 24%.
看来只要你继续使用钢铁盔甲
It appears that the continued use of the Iron Man suit
中毒的速度会愈快
is accelerating your condition.
另一块钯能量板又耗损光了
Another core has been depleted.
它们耗损得很快
God, they're running out quick.
我模拟过每一种已知的元素
I have run simulations on every known element,
没有一种能替代钯元素
and none can serve as a viable replacement for the palladium core.
你的时闲和选择已经不多了
You are running out of both time and options.
很不幸 让你活命的装置
Unfortunately, the device that's keeping you alive
也会害死你
is also killing you.
波兹小姐来了
Miss Potts is approaching.
-我建议你立刻告诉… -静音
-I recommend that you inform her... -Mute.
你在开玩笑吗？
Is this a joke?
-你在想什么？ -什么？
-What are you thinking? -What?
-你在想什么？ -我在想我很忙
-What are you thinking? -Hey, I'm thinking I'm busy.
你又在生气
And you're angry about something.
你感冒了吗？我不想被传染
Do you have the sniffles? I don't wanna get sick.
-你是不是把… -继续做你的事
-Did you just donate... -Keep your business.
我们所有的现代艺术收藏捐给…
...our entire modern art collection to the...
-美国童子军协会 -美国童子军协会？
-Boy Scouts ofAmerica. -...Boy Scouts ofAmerica?
那是很有意义的组织
Yes. It is a worthwhile organisation.
我没有亲自检查过木箱 不过基本上没错
I didn't physically check the crates but, basically, yes.
而且不是我们的收藏 是我的收藏 不要介意
And it's not "our" collection, it's my collection. No offence.
不会 你知道吗？我有权讨论“我们”的收藏
No, you know what? I think I'm actually entitled to say "our" collection
因为我花了十年整理
considering the time that I put in, over 10 years, curating that.
都是为了减税 我需要那个
It was a tax write-off. I needed that.
我只有8千零11件事…
You know, there's only about 8,011 things
必须跟你讨论
that I really need to talk to you about.
机械手 别恍神 专心点
Dummy. Hey, stop spacing out.
布里奇伯特已经加工了部分
The Bridgeport's already machining that part.
博览会完全是浪费时闲
The Expo is a gigantic waste of time.
你感冒没好之前得戴口罩
I need you to wear a surgical mask until you're feeling better.
-好不好？ -你很没礼貌
-Is that okay? -That's rude.
没有什么比博览会对我更重要
There's nothing more important to me than the Expo.
那是我最关心的事情
It's my primary point of concern.
-不知你为何… -博览会只是你的虚荣心作祟
-I don't know why you're... -The Expo is your ego gone crazy.
哇 你看看
Wow. Look at that.
这是现代艺术 我要挂起来
That's modern art. That's going up.
-你一定是在开玩笑 -我要马上把它挂起来
-You've got to be kidding. -I'm gonna put this up right now.
-这很重要 -斯塔克工业乱成一团
-This is vital. -Stark is in complete disarray.
-你明白吗？ -不对 我们的股价涨停板
-You understand that? -No. Our stocks have never been higher.
-那是从经营者的角度来看 -你…如果很乱
-Yes, from a managerial standpoint. -You are... Well, if it's messy,
-那就绕回去 -让我举例说明
-then let's double back. -Let me give you an example.
-再谈刚才那件事 -不 不
-Let's move on to another subject. -No, no, no, no.
你不准把巴奈特・纽曼的画拿下来
You are not taking down the Barnett Newman
-继续挂着！ -我不是拿下来
-and hanging that up! -I'm not taking it down.
只是取代它
I'm just replacing it with this.
-看看我得到了什么 -好吧 随你便
-Let's see what I can get going here. -Okay, fine.
我想说的是…我们拿到合约
My point is, we have already awarded contracts
-风力发电场的合约 -别提到风
-to the wind farm people. -Yeah. Don't say "wind farm."
-你会害我撇风 -还有废气处理厂的合约
-I'm already feeling gassy. -And to the plastic plantation tree,
那是你的点子 这些人都领我们的薪水
which was your idea, by the way. Those people are on payroll...
-一切都是我的点子 -…你不会再做决定
-Everything was my idea. -...and you won't make a decision.
我不再关心自由派议题了
I don't care about the liberal agenda any more.
超无聊的！我要给你一个无聊警告
It's boring. Boring. I'm giving you a boring alert.
-你去做  -做什么？
-You do it. -I do what?
这点子太赞了 我刚想出来的 你来管理公司
Excellent idea. I just figured this out. You run the company.
是啊 我一直在试着管理公司
Yeah, I'm trying to run the company.
小辣椒 我需要你管理公司
Pepper, I need you to run the company.
-嗯 不是叫你试着去做而是亲自去做 -你不应该…
-Well, stop trying to do it and do it. -You will not
-告诉我这个消息 -我不是要你去试着做…
-give me the information... -I'm not asking you to try...
-…为了…  -我要求你
-...in order to... -I'm asking you
亲自去做 我需要你去做
to physically do it. I need you to do it.
-我一直试着在做呀！ -小辣椒 你没在听我说话！
-I am trying to do it. -Pepper, you're not listening to me!
-不 你都没在听 -我要你当首席执行官
-No, you are not listening to me. -I'm trying to make you CEO.
你为什么不肯？
Why won't you let me?
-你喝了不少吧？ -叶绿素汁
-Have you been drinking? -Chlorophyll.
我正式任命你为斯塔克工业首席执行官
I hereby irrevocably appoint you chairman and CEO of Stark Industries,
马上生效
effective immediately.
就这样
Yeah, done deal. Okay?
信不信由你 我想了很久
I've actually given this a fair amount of thought,
我甚至找了一些人选
believe it or not. Doing a bit of headhunting, so to speak,
认真思考谁是最适合的人选
trying to figure out who a worthy successor would be.
后来才发现…
And then I realised
就是你 一直都是你
it's you. It's always been you.
我还以为会有法律问题
I thought there'd be a legal issue,
不过我是可以指定我的接班人
but actually I'm capable of appointing my successor.
也就是你
My successor being you.
恭喜了
Congratulations?
-拿去 拿去嘛 -我不知道该怎么想
-Take it, just take it. -I don't know what to think.
别想 喝下去
Don't think. Drink.
就这样
There you go.
“摩纳哥赛车大赛”
公证人来了 你能过来签一些转让文件吗？
The notary's here! Can you please come sign the transfer paperwork?
我正在爽着呢
I'm on happy time.
-对不起  -这是哪一招？
-Sorry. -What the hell was that?
这叫综合格斗 才刚流行了三周时间
It's called mixed martial arts. It's been around for three weeks.
这叫下流拳击 流行很久了
It's called dirty boxing. There's nothing new about it.
好吧 来吧
All right, put them up. Come on.
我保证这是唯一一次我请求你把你的公司转让给我
I promise you this is the only time I will ask you to sign over your company.
请签上名字的缩写
I need you to initial each box.
第一课 千万别把眼神移开…
Lesson one. Never take your eye off...
我不玩了
That's it. I'm done.
-你叫什么 小姐？ -罗许曼 娜塔莉・罗许曼
-What's your name, lady? -Rushman. Natalie Rushman.
过来 请上擂台
Front and centre. Come into the church.
-你不会是真的想要她… -法官说了就算 我就是法官
-No. You're seriously not gonna ask... -If it pleases the court, which it does.
-没问题 -抱歉 他是个怪人
-It's no problem. -I'm sorry. He's very eccentric.
什么？
What?
-你能不能教她一下？ -没问题
-Can you give her a lesson? -No problem.
-小辣椒 -干嘛？
-Pepper. -What?
-她是谁？ -她来自法律部
-Who is she? -She is from legal.
她可能害你吃上性骚扰官司
And she is potentially a very expensive sexual harassment lawsuit
-如果你再这样盯着她看 -我需要新的助理 老板
-if you keep ogling her like that. -I need a new assistant, boss.
我有三个很有潜力的人选
Yes, and I've got three excellent potential candidates.
等你和他们面试
They're lined up and ready to meet you.
我没时闲面试 我现在就要一个 我觉得是她
I don't have time to meet. I need someone now. I feel like it's her.
绝对不是
No, it's not.
-你有没有打过拳？  -有
-You ever boxed before? -I have, yes.
像是搏击健身操？塑身操？瑜咖之类的？
What, like, the Tae Bo? Booty Boot Camp? Crunch? Something like that?
-你的姓怎么拼 娜塔莉？ -R一U一S一H一M一A一N
-How do I spell your name, Natalie? -R-U-S-H-M-A-N.
-你要Google她？ -我以为我是在盯着她
-What, are you gonna google her now? -I thought I was ogling her.
-哇 她很厉害嘛 -你很无聊 知道吗？
-Wow. Very, very impressive individual. -You're so predictable, you know that?
她精通法语、意大利语和拉丁语
She's fluent in French, Italian, Russian, Latin.
-谁会说拉丁语呀？ -没有人会说拉丁语
-Who speaks Latin? -No one speaks Latin.
-没人会说拉丁语？ -那是快消失的语言
-No one speaks Latin? -It's a dead language.
你会读拉丁文 或者你会写拉丁文
You can read Latin or you can write Latin,
-但你不会说拉丁语… -你在东京当过模特儿吗？
-but you can't speak Latin... -Did you model in Tokyo?
-她就当过 -呃…
-'Cause she modeled in Tokyo. -Well...
我需要她 她样样俱全
I need her. She's got everything that I need.
第一条铁律：死盯着对手
Rule number one, never take your eye off your opponent.
我的天啊！
Oh, my God!
-哈皮！ -这就是我说的！
-Happy! -That's what I'm talking about.
-我只是滑倒  -是吗？
-I just slipped. -You did?
-真的 -看起来像是技术性击倒
-Yeah. -Looks like a TKO to me.
我需要你的指印
Just... I need your impression.
你很沉稳 非常成熟…
You have a quiet reserve. I don't know, you have an old soul.
-我是说你的指纹 -好啊
-I meant your fingerprint. -Right.
-我们干得怎么样？ -太棒了 就快搞定了
-So, how are we doing? -Great. Just wrapping up. Hey.
-你才是老板 -还有事吗 斯塔克先生？
-You're the boss. -Will that be all, Mr Stark?
-没了 -没事了 罗许曼小姐
-No. -Yes, that will be all, Ms Rushman.
谢谢你
Thank you very much.
-我要这一个 -不行
-I want one. -No.
（摩纳哥）
这里是欧洲 不管发生什么事
You know, it's Europe. Whatever happens the next 20 minutes,
-顺其自然 -顺其自然？顺其自然？
-just go with it. -Go with it? Go with what?
斯塔克先生？
Mr Stark?
旅程顺利吧？
Hello. How was your flight?
很好 真的很高兴见到你
It was excellent. Boy, it's nice to see you.
有位摩纳哥赛车俱乐部的摄影师 可以吗？
We have one photographer from the ACM, if you don't mind. Okay?
-你是几时雇用她的？ -什么？是你逼我的
-When did this happen? -What? You made me do it.
-我逼你做什么？ -微笑 看这里
-I made you do what? -You quit. Smile. Look right there.
表情不要太生硬
Stop acting constipated.
-表要露出你的鼻孔 -你的老毛病就是不改
-Don't flare your nostrils. -You are so predictable.
-太令人吃惊了 -看这里
-That's the amazing thing. -Right this way.
-你看起来美呆了！ -什么啊 多谢夸奖
-You look fantastic. -Why, thank you very much.
我知道我很不专业 有什么行程？
But that's unprofessional. What's on the docket?
9点半有个饭局
You have a 9:30 dinner.
-太好了 我11点会到 -当然了
-Perfect. I'll be there at 11 :00. -Absolutely.
-这是我们的桌位？ -这可以是
-Is this us? -It can be.
-太好了 去搞定吧 -好的
-Great. Make it us. -Okay.
-马斯克先生 你好吗？ -嗨 小辣椒
-Mr Musk. How are you? -Hi, Pepper.
-恭喜你升职  -谢谢你
-Congratulations on the promotion. -Thank you very much.
伊隆 梅林引擎棒呆了
Elon, how's it going? Those Merlin engines are fantastic.
谢了 我想打造电力喷射机
Thank you. Yeah, I've got an idea for an electric jet.
-真的假的？  -真的
-You do? -Yeah.
那就一起合作吧
Then we'll make it work.
-你要按摩吗？ -哦 天啊 不
-You want a massage? -Oh, God. No,
-我不需要按摩 -我叫娜塔莉安排
-I don't want a massage. -I'll have Natalie make an...
-我不要娜塔莉安排任何事 -不想让你紧张
-I don't want Natalie to do... -Don't want you tense.
随便说一下 我不是故意不告诉你
By the way, I didn't mean to spring this on you.
多谢了喔
Thank you very much.
-你穿绿色不是很好看 -哦 拜托
-Green is not your best colour. -Oh, please.
托尼！是你吗？
Anthony! Is that you?
-我最讨厌的家伙 -嘿
-My least favourite person on Earth. -Hey, pal.
-贾斯汀・汉默 -还好吗？
-Justin Hammer. -How you doing?
你不是唯一开名车的有钱人
You're not the only rich guy here with a fancy car.
这是《浮华世界》的克莉丝汀
You know Christine Everhart from Vanity Fair.
-你们俩认识？ -嗨
-You guys know each other? -Hi.
-是的 -是的
-Yes. -Yes.
-对 但是并不熟 -对
-Yes, roughly. -We do.
对了 大新闻 斯塔克工业全新的首席执行官
BTW, big story. The new CEO of Stark Industries.
-我知道了 -恭喜了
-I know. I know. -Congratulations.
我不访问你的话会被主编骂死
My editor will kill me if I don't grab a quote for our Powerful Women issue.
-是吗？ -没错
-Can I? -Sure.
她要在《浮华世界》专访我
She's actually doing a big spread on me for Vanity Fair.
我顺便让她访问你 你懂的
I thought I'd throw her a bone, you know.
-没错 -没错？
-Right. -Right?
她去年帮托尼“做”过一次专访
Well, she did quite a spread on Tony last year.
然后也写了一篇报导
And she wrote a story as well.
-令人印象深刻 -写得很好
-It was very impressive. -That was good.
-非常好  -谢谢你
-Very well done. -Thank you.
-我要去洗手闲  -别丢下我
-I'm gonna go wash. -Don't leave me.
-老兄 你好吗？  -好得很
-Hey, buddy. How you doing? -I'm all right.
-你帅呆了  -别靠这么近
-Looking gorgeous. -Please, this is tough.
-我能问你 这是… -奶酪
-Can I ask you... Is this the first time... -Fromage.
-说“布利干酪” -…你们以前认识吗？
-Say, "Brie." -...that you guys have seen each other?
天啊 真恶！受不了！
God, that's so awful.
…你们在听证会后第一次见面
Listen, is it the first time you've seen each other since the Senate?
自从他的合约被取消以后？
Since he got his contract revoked...
-不是 只是暂缓 -…当你企图…
-Actually, it's on hold. -...when you were attempting to...
我听到的可不是这样 与“暂缓”不同的是…
That's not what I heard. What's the difference between "hold"
-和“取消”？事实吗？ -是的 是什么？
-and "cancelled"? The truth? -Yes, what is?
不是 事实是…把录音机关了吧
No. The truth is... Why don't we put that away?
事实是…我想在你的博览会展示产品
The truth is, I'm actually hoping to present something at your Expo.
如果你发明能用的东西
Well, if you invent something that works,
我一定会替你保留展示厅
I'll make sure I get you a slot.
-他只是在开玩笑  -什么？
-Mr Stark, your corner table is ready. -Yes?
其实今年我有一个机会 是的 我有
I actually have a slot this year. Yes, I do.
-汉默需要“机会”啦  -不是啦
-Hammer needs a slot, Christine. -We kid, yeah.
我们常常开玩笑
We kid. We're kidders.
“血液毒性：53%"
有更糟的点子吗？
Got any other bad ideas?
托尼！
Tony!
托尼和我… 托尼…我爱托尼
Tony and I... Tony... I love Tony Stark.
他也爱我 我们不是竞争对手
Tony loves me. We're not competitors.
他退出军售行业以后促使汉默工业加速发展
Him being out of the picture created tremendous opportunities for Hammer Industries, you know?
-我和托尼之间的做的任何事… -用途是什么
-Everything that Tony and I do... -Well, what's the use of having...
-有的是良性竞争… -拥有一辆赛车…
-...is a healthy... -...and owning a race car...
-…就是要比赛 -…不然拥有赛车要干嘛？
-...competition. -...if you don't drive it?
他要赛车？
Is he driving?
娜塔莉 娜塔莉！
Natalie. Natalie!
-波兹小姐？ -你知道他要赛车吗？
-Yes, Miss Potts? -Did you know about this?
我也是现在才知道的
This is the first that I have known of it.
他不能赛车
This... This cannot happen.
我了解 我该怎么帮你？
Absolutely. I understand. How can I help you?
-哈皮呢？  -他在外面
-Where's Happy? -He's waiting outside.
-去找他 我需要哈皮 -马上就去
-Okay, get him. I need Happy. -Right away.
托尼他…
Tony's... You know, he...
我和托尼不是竞争对手 你明白了吗？
We're not competitive. You know what I mean?
是的 是的
Yeah, yeah, yeah. You know,
-恕我失陪一下 -你能不能把你写的念给我听？
-can you excuse me just one second? -Just read me what you wrote.
-我会的 等会儿 -读给我听
-I will. I will, after. -Just read it back to me.
但我得先打通电话
But I have to make one quick phone call.
-你要去哪里？ -这太棒了
-Where are you going? -This is great.
-等一下会有鱼子酱哦  -这东西太棒了
-I've got some caviar coming. -This is great stuff.
-我马上回来 -看！
-I'll be right back. -Look!
那是史塔克
That's Stark.
快走！
Go, go!
坐好了
Hang on.
-把公事箱给我  -拿去
-Give me the case. -Here. Take it.
-钥匙呢？  -在我的口袋
-Where's the key? -It's in my pocket.
有车！
Car!
天啊
Oh, my God!
-你没事吧？ -没事
-Are you okay? -Yeah.
-你是想撞我还是撞他？ -我只想吓吓他
-Were you heading for me or him? -I was trying to scare him.
-因为我分不清楚！ -你疯啦？
-'Cause I can't tell! -Are you out of your mind?
-更好的安保…  -快上车！
-Better security. -Get in the car right now!
我受到攻击！我们需要更好的安保
I was attacked! We need better security.
-快上车！ -你是CEO 需要更好的安保
-Get in the car! -You're CEO. Better security measures.
天啊 真丢脸
God, it's embarrassing.
两年来第一次休假…
First vacation in two years.
我的天啊！
Oh, my God!
-我撞到他了！ -再撞他一次 再一次！
-I got him! -Hit him again. Hit him again.
把箱子给我
Football.
-我撞到他了！ -把公事箱拿去！
-I got him! -Take the case! Take it!
-把公事箱拿去！ -快拿给他！
-Take the case! -Give him the case!
别再撞了！
Stop banging the car!
冷静
Calm down.
天啊！天啊！
God! God!
把公事箱给我 拜托！快点！
Give me the case! Please! Come on!
你…你输了
You... You lose.
你输了 你输了 斯塔克
You lose. You lose, Stark.
我们查过他的指纹
啥都没有 连名字都查不到
我们要去哪里？
那里
我们甚至不确定他会说英语
他连一个字都没说
5分钟
挺先进的科技 不过转速有点低
Pretty decent tech. Cycles per second were a little low.
你大可以把转速加倍
You could have doubled up your rotations.
让反能量穿过离子化电浆管道
You focused the repulsor energy through ionized plasma channels.
有用 但效率不高
It's effective. Not very efficient.
不过还是挺不错的仿冒品
But it's a passable knock-off.
我不懂 只要微调一下
I don't get it. A little fine tuning,
你就能靠它赚不少钱
you could have made a solid paycheck.
你可以卖给北韩、中国和伊朗
You could have sold it to North Korea, China, Iran,
或是直接在黑市兜售
or gone right to the black market.
看来你的朋友都是B咖
You look like you got friends in low places.
你的家族是小偷和屠夫
You come from a family of thieves and butchers.
你跟每一个罪人一样
And now, like all guilty men,
想要重写你的历史
you try to rewrite your own history.
忘了斯塔克家族害死的人命
And you forget all the lives the Stark family has destroyed.
我的设计图是哪愉来的？
Speaking of thieves, where did you get this design?
我父亲 安东・万科
My father. Anton Vanko.
没听过他
Well, I never heard of him.
你没死是因为我父亲
My father is the reason you're alive.
我没死是因为你想杀死我
The reason I'm alive is 'cause you had a shot, you took it,
你却失败
you missed.
是吗？
Did I?
如果你能让上帝流血
If you can make God bleed,
人们就不会相信她
the people will cease to believe in him.
当水中有血迹 就会引来鲨鱼
And there will be blood in the water. And the sharks will come.
我只要坐在这里看
The truth, all I have to do is sit here and watch
世人就会把你吞噬
as the world will consume you.
你要在哪里看世人把我吞噬？
Where will you be watching the world consume me from?
没错 你的牢房 我会送你一块香皂
That's right. A prison cell. I'll send you a bar of soap.
托尼 在你走之前
Hey, Tony. Before you go,
钯中毒的死法…很痛苦
palladium in the chest, painful way to die.
真是难以置信 这证明瓶子里的魔鬼已经被放出来了
It's just unbelievable. It proves that the genie is out of the bottle
他却还像个无头苍蝇
and this man has no idea what he's doing.
他把钢铁侠当作玩具
He thinks of the Iron Man weapon as a toy.
斯塔克先生在听证会上很坚决地说
I was at a hearing where Mr Stark, in fact, was adamant
钢铁盔甲不会在任何地方出现
that these suits can't exist anywhere else,
不在任何地方出现 从未在任何地方出现
don't exist anywhere else, never will exist anywhere else,
至少在未来的5至10年内…
at least for five to 10 years,
但我们在摩纳哥却看到 “钢铁盔甲出现了”
and here we are in Monaco realising, "These suits exist now."
静音
Mute.
说真的 他应该颁奖章给我
He should be giving me a medal. That's the truth.
-那是什么？ -你在机上的餐点
-What is that? -This is your in-flight meal.
这是你做的？
Did you just make that?
对 你以为我这3小时在干嘛？
Yeah. Where do you think I've been for three hours?
托尼？
Tony,
你有什么在瞒着我？
what are you not telling me?
我完全不想回家
I don't want to go home. At all.
取消我的生日派对
Let's cancel my birthday party and...
我们在欧洲 去威尼斯住西普亚尼饭店
We're in Europe. Let's go to Venice, Cipriani.
-记得吗？  -记得
-Remember? -Oh, yes.
住在那里…
It's a great place to
-…有益身体健康 -现在不是好时机
-be healthy. -I don't think this is the right time.
一大堆烂摊子要收拾
We're in kind of a mess.
没错 所以才是好时机
Yeah, but maybe that's why it's the best time.
-因为那时我们… -我身为首席执行官
-'Cause then we... -Well, I think as the CEO,
必须坐镇公司
I need to show up.
你身为首席执行官有权利离开
As CEO, you are entitled to a leave.
-离开？  -员工休假
-A leave? -A company retreat.
-休假？在这种紧要关头？ -坐坐车就行
-A retreat? During a time like this? -Just a ride.
我们只要再充电就会想出办法
Well, I'm just saying, to recharge our batteries and figure it all out.
不是每个人都靠电池过活 托尼
Not everybody runs on batteries, Tony.
“请享用洋芋泥”
他来了！
Hey, there he is.
他来了
There he is.
很高兴你来了 欢迎
What an absolute pleasure. Welcome.
真是的
Oh, goodness gracious.
把我朋友的手铐解开
Can we get the handcuffs off my friend here?
原谅我 我是你的超级粉丝
Forgive me, I'm sorry. I'm such a huge fan of yours.
我不想让你留下坏印象
I didn't want to make a first impression like this.
他又不是动物
He's not an animal. Come on.
他是个人 谢谢你
He's a human being. Thank you.
我们不会有事
We're fine.
我叫贾斯汀・汉默
My name is Justin Hammer.
我想跟你做点生意 请坐
I'd like to do some business with you. Please sit.
吃吧 今天有什么菜色？
Dig in. What do we have today, Jack?
-鲑鱼佐酱汁 -鲑鱼佐酱汁？
-We have some salmon carpaccio. -Salmon carpaccio.
你要什么我们都有
Anything you want here, we got it.
我喜欢先吃甜点 这是从旧金山空运送来的
I like my dessert first. I had this flown in from San Francisco.
不过是意大利式甜点
It's Italian, though.
有机冰淇淋
Organic ice cream.
我超爱吃甜食 看来你也很想杀死托尼・斯塔克
I got a sweet tooth. Apparently you do, too, for Tony Stark.
当我看到你在赛车道攻击他
What I saw you do to Tony Stark on that track,
你像天兵神将站在他面前
how you stepped up to him in front of God and everybody,
大家都觉得太神了
that was... Wow!
你向我传达一个信息
You spoke to me with what you did.
我也知道你知道我一定会听
And I know that you knew that I'd be listening.
所以我不能让他们把你送走
This is why I couldn't bear to have you shipped off
白白浪费你的才能
to God knows where. It would have been such a waste of talent.
不过我想给你一个建议
But if I might make a suggestion,
不要就这样跑去想杀死他
you know, you don't just go and try and kill the guy.
我的想法是…要是我就会扼杀他的成就
I think, if I may, you go after his legacy.
那才叫干掉他
That's what you kill.
我们有很多地方很像
You and me, we are a lot alike in a lot of ways.
唯一的不同是我有资源
The only difference between you and I is that I have resources.
我认为你需要我的资源
I think, if I may, you need my resources.
当你的靠山 一位赞助人
Someone behind you, a benefactor.
我想当那个人
I'd like to be that guy.
你会说英语吗？我可以找一个翻译
Okay. Do you speak English? Because I can get a translator.
我不确定你听懂我说的话
I don't know. Have you been understanding everything I'm saying?
很好的人
Very good, man.
-超好的 老兄 -很好 老兄
-Very good, man. -Very good, man.
什么事？
Yes?
我要我的小鸟
I want my bird.
-小鸟？你要一只小鸟？ -我要我的小鸟
-A bird? You want a bird? -I want my bird.
我可以给你十只小鸟
I can get you a bird. I can get you 10 birds.
我要我的小鸟
I want my bird.
好 没有不可能的事
Well, okay. Nothing's impossible. I could...
你是说你在俄罗斯的小鸟？
Are we talking about... Is this a bird back in Russia?
尽管发生摩纳哥事件
Yes, but the fundamentals of the company are still very, very strong
-本公司的基础仍然很牢固 -是的 当然
-despite the events in Monaco. -Yes, of course.
-美联社要你发言 -把这份声明稿传真给他们
-The AP wants a quote. -Don't tell him. Fax them...
他在哪里？
Where is he?
-他不想被打扰 -他在楼下
-He doesn't want to be disturbed. -He's downstairs.
-在摩纳哥发生什么了？ -但是…
-...what happened in Monaco? -Yes, but...
但是他一直出状况
But his continuing erratic behaviour
会让大众质疑
may lead many people to ask themselves,
他能否保护我们？
"Can this man still protect us?"
钢铁侠一直在保护我们 摩纳哥发生的事就是证明
Iron Man never stopped protecting us. The events in Monaco proved that.
搜寻完毕 长官 安东・万科是苏联物理学家
Query complete, sir. Anton Vanko was a Soviet physicist
1963年叛逃到美国
who defected to the United States in 1963.
但是他被指控是间谍 1967年被驱逐出境
However, he was accused of espionage and was deported in 1967.
他儿子 伊万 也是物理学家
His son, Ivan, who is also a physicist,
因为在苏联时期倒卖武器级钸材料给巴基斯坦
was convicted of selling Soviet-era weapons-grade plutonium to Pakistan,
被判在科佩斯克监狱服刑15年
and served 15 years in Kopeisk prison.
没有其它记录
No further records exist.
托尼？你得上楼把情势控制住
Tony, you gotta get upstairs and get on top of this situation right now.
我一整天都在和国民兵通电话
Listen. I've been on the phone with the National Guard all day,
说服他们不要开坦克车过来
trying to talk them out of rolling tanks up the PCH,
撞破你的大门 拿走这些
knocking down your front door and taking these.
他们想拿走你的钢铁盔甲
They're gonna take your suits, Tony, okay?
他们懒得跟你玩游戏
They're sick of the games.
你说20年内没人能拥有这种科技
You said nobody else would possess this technology for 20 years.
猜怎么着…昨天就有人拥有它
Well, guess what? Somebody else had it yesterday.
而且不再是理论
It's not theoretical any more.
你有在听吗？
Are you listening to me?
-你还好吧？ -走吧
-Are you okay? -Let's go.
-你没事吧？ -我要到我的办公桌
-You all right? -Yeah, I should get to my desk.
-看到雪茄盒吗？  -看到了
-See that cigar box? -Yeah.
那是钯能量板
It's palladium.
这玩意应该冒烟吗？
Is that supposed to be smoking?
中子受损 是方舟反应炉壁在冒烟
If you must know, it's neutron damage. It's from the reactor wall.
这玩意在你体内？
You had this in your body?
你脖子上的字谜又是怎么回事？
And how about the high-tech crossword puzzle on your neck?
擦伤的痕迹
Road rash.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-你在看什么？ -我在看你
-What are you looking at? -I'm looking at you.
你不必要一个人当救世主
You wanna do this whole lone gunslinger act
你不必光靠自己
and it's unnecessary. You don't have to do this alone.
我也很想相信你说的
You know, I wish I could believe that. I really do.
但是你得信任我
But you've gotta trust me.
一般人对我有误解 我很清楚我在做什么
Contrary to popular belief, I know exactly what I'm doing.
（纽约皇后区）
这是我的军火工厂 我的寒舍
This is where we do it. This is my humble abode.
你可以安静地工作 当死人很好玩吧？
You can work in absolute peace. Must be fun to be dead, right?
没有压力？
No pressure.
它们在那里 我很兴奋 它们可以随时作战
Here they are. I'm very excited. They're combat-ready.
我也许算错了一些数据
I may have done a few miscalculations
太急着利用原型大量制造
and rushed the prototype into production.
没办法 我是个急性子
Sue me, I'm enthusiastic.
随便到处看看
Go ahead, take a look around.
你最好不要那么做
You don't wanna do that.
我们要先设定一些密码 你才能开始操作
You'll be able to access that as soon as we generate some encrypted pass codes.
快去设定密码给他使用
Can we generate some encrypted pass codes?
“输入密码” 设定哪些密码 杰克
Get some of those encrypted pass codes, Jack.
“准许进入”
算了
Never mind, I...
哇 好吧 好样的
Wow. Okay. Good stuff.
-什么？ -你的软件是狗屎
-Sorry? -Software shit.
你很厉害
You're good.
你就这样破解了防火墙
You really blasted in past the firewall there.
让我给你看你要在哪里工作
Let me show you where you're gonna be working primarily.
看吧 仔细看吧
Go ahead, take a look.
你看看 很棒 对吧？
Get a good look at that. That's something, isn't it?
那些钢铁盔甲只是展示品
You know, those are really just for show and tell.
每套价值1亿2千5百70万…等等！噢糟了
They're $1 25.7 million a pop, so... Wait! Oh, gosh.
老天 快找人上来帮忙
Jesus Christ. Get somebody up here.
那是驾驶员的位置
That's where the pilot goes.
不过我找不到自愿者
I'm having a tough time finding volunteers.
我会搞定 别乱碰
I'll take care of that, just leave it.
你要它们做什么？
What you want them do?
长期来说 我要它们让我能和国防部签下25年的合约
Well, long term, I want them to put me in the Pentagon for the next 25 years.
我要让钢铁侠看起来像古董
I want to make Iron Man look like an antique.
我要去斯塔克博览会
I wanna go to that Stark Expo,
我要在托尼家的前院拉屎
I wanna take a dump in Tony's front yard.
你知道我们说什么吗？
You know what I'm talking about?
-我办得到 没问题 -是吗？
-I can do that. No problem. -Yeah?
棒呆了 我喜欢
Hey, fabulous! I love it.
我就说他是我们的救星吧？我有预感
Hey, this is our guy. Didn't I tell you? I had a feeling.
“钯浓度：89%"
你今晚想戴哪一支手表？
Do you know which watch you'd like to wear tonight, Mr Stark?
我等一下会看
I'll give them a look.
我应该取消派对 对吧？
I should cancel the party.
-大概吧 -是的
-Probably. -Yeah.
-因为真的… -不是时候
-'Cause it's... -Ill-timed.
这会发出错误讯息
Right, sends the wrong message.
很不恰当
Inappropriate.
够烈吗？
Is that dirty enough for you?
金色表面、棕色表带 积家牌手表 让我看看
Gold face, brown band. The Jaeger. I'll give that a look.
拿过来
Bring them over here.
我要戴那支 你可以…
I'll take that. Why don't you...
老实说 我摸不清你的底细
I gotta say it. It's hard to get a read on you.
-你来自哪里？ -法律部门
-Where are you from? -Legal.
我能问你一个假设性问题吗？
Can I ask you a question, hypothetically?
这问题有点怪
Bit odd.
如果这是你最后一次生日派对
If this was your last birthday party you were ever gonna have,
你会怎么庆祝？
how would you celebrate it?
想跟谁做什么就做什么
I'd do whatever I wanted to do with whoever I wanted to do it with.
-晚上好  -晚上好
-Good evening. -Good evening.
是的长官 我了解
Yes, sir, I understand.
不 没有这必要 我会处理
No. No, sir, that will not be necessary. I'll handle it.
我保证24小时内
Sir, I personally guarantee that within 24 hours,
钢铁侠就会回到他的岗位
Iron Man will be back on watch.
嘿 小辣椒
Hey, Pepper.
我要走了 我得出去透透气
I'm going to go get some air.
怎么了？
What's wrong?
-我不知道该怎么做  -这是在开玩笑吧
-I don't know what to do. -You gotta be kidding me.
-够了 我要…小辣椒  -不 不 不 别打给任何人
-That's it. I'm making... Pepper. -No, no, no. Don't call anyone.
太扯了 我才刚替他挂保证
This is ridiculous. I just stuck my neck out for this guy.
我知道 让我搞定
I know. I know. I get it.
我来搞定好吗？让我来搞定
I'm gonna handle it, okay? Just let me handle it.
快点搞定 不然我就亲自来
Handle it. Or I'm gonna have to.
我最常被问的问题是：
You know, the question I get asked most often is,
你穿了钢铁盔甲要怎么上厕所？
"Tony, how do you go to the bathroom in the suit?"
就像这样
Just like that.
这家伙超会开轰趴 对吧？
Does this guy know how to throw a party or what?
我爱你…
I love you.
不可思议 谢谢你 托尼
Unbelievable! Thank you so much.
谢谢你安排这么美好的夜晚
Tony, we all thank you so much for such a wonderful night.
我们该说晚安了 谢谢大家光临
And we're gonna say good night now, and thank you all for coming.
不…不…等等…等等…
No, no, no, we can't... Wait, wait, wait.
我们都还没切蛋糕、吹蜡烛
We didn't have the cake. We didn't blow out the candles.
你已经失控了 相信我
You're out of control, okay? Trust me on this one, okay?
-你才美的失控呢 -该上床睡觉了
-You're out of control, gorgeous. -It's time to go to bed. It's time.
-再亲我一下 -你不会
-Give me another smooch. -You're not going to be
-对此感兴趣的 -来吧 知道你要的
-happy about this. -Come on, you know you want to.
你刚才尿钢铁盔甲里
You just peed the suit.
-我知道 它有过滤系统  -它不性感
-I know. It has a filtration system. -It's not sexy.
过滤出来的水可以喝
You could drink that water.
让大家回家吧 时候不早了
Just send everybody home, okay? It's time to...
-你说了算数 -好的
-If you say so. -Okay.
我拿这个 你拿这个
I'll take this, you take that.
小辣椒波兹
Pepper Potts.
她说的对 派对结束了
She's right. The party's over.
派对1个半小时前就该结束了
Then again, the party was over for me, like, an hour and a half ago.
15分钟后…开始续摊
The after-party starts in 15 minutes.
如果有人 包括小辣椒不喜欢这个 大门就在那里
And if anybody, Pepper, doesn't like it, there's the door.
丢！
Hit!
Pull!
再丢！
让我来！
我猜她喜欢加拉戈尔
I think she wants the Gallagher!
你打中了！
我只要说一次
I'm only gonna say this once.
滚出去
Get out.
你不配穿钢铁盔甲 脱掉它
You don't deserve to wear one of these. Shut it down!
小戈
Goldstein.
是的 斯塔克先生
Yes, Mr Stark?
别怕 音乐给它摧下去
Give me a phat beat to beat my buddy's ass to.
我叫你把钢铁盔甲脱掉
I told you to shut it down.
把它放回去 免得有人受伤
Now, put that thing back where you found it before someone gets hurt.
真来呀？
Really?
抱歉 钢铁侠不需要助手
Sorry, pal, but Iron Man doesn't have a sidekick.
吃我这一招！
Sidekick this!
玩够了吗？
Had enough?
-娜塔莉！  -波兹小姐
-Natalie! -Miss Potts.
少来了 我早就看穿你的诡计
Don't you "Miss Potts" me! I'm on to you.
你来了以后就…
You know what? Ever since you came here...
小辣椒！
Pepper!
快闪人吧！
Get out of here. Get out of here.
你要这玩意？拿去！
You want it? Take it!
把手放下
Put your hand down.
你自以为有当钢铁侠的料吗？
You think you got what it takes to wear that suit?
我们不必打来打去
We don't have to do this, Tony.
你想当战争机器 开火呀
You wanna be the War Machine, take your shot.
-快放下！  -你想开火吗？
-Put it down! -You gonna take a shot?
-放下来！  -不！
-Put it down! -No!
-放下来 托尼！  -快开火！
-Drop it, Tony! -Take it.
（爱德华空军基地）
爱德华兹控制塔 我是詹姆斯・罗德中校
Edwards Tower, this is Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes,
从机场以东3哩外进场 处于5000英尺…
inbound from three miles east at 5,000 feet...
（要求降落在22号停机坪）
中校
Colonel.
少校
Major.
是啊
Yeah.
把它带进去吧
Let's take it inside.
净空这区域！
Clear the area.
先生！
Sir!
请你从甜甜圈上下来！
I'm gonna have to ask you to exit the doughnut.
我不想加入你的超人男孩团体
I told you I don't wanna join your super-secret boy band.
我记得 你什么都是自己来
No, no, no. See, I remember, you do everything yourself.
-结果怎么样？ -结果…结果…
-How's that working out for you? -It's... It's... It's...
抱歉 我不想引起你的误会
I'm sorry. I don't wanna get off on the wrong foot.
我该看你的眼罩还是眼睛？
Do I look at the patch or the eye?
老实说 我有点宿醉
Honestly, I'm a bit hung over.
我不确定你是真人还是幻觉
I'm not sure if you're real or if I'm having...
我是真人
I am very real.
我是你见过最真实的人
I'm the realest person you're ever gonna meet.
-我真走运 这里的员工呢？ -这看起来不太妙
-Just my luck. Where's the staff here? -That's not looking so good.
我有过更糟的状况
I've been worse.
我净空整个区域
We've secured the perimeter,
不过最好不要花太多时闲
but I don't think we should hold it for too much longer.
-你被开除了 -这由不得你来决定
-You're fired. -That's not up to you.
托尼 这是罗曼诺夫特工
Tony, I want you to meet Agent Romanoff.
我是神盾局的卧底特工
I'm a S.H.I.E.L.D. shadow.
当我们知道你病了 福瑞局长就派我来观察你
Once we knew you were ill, I was tasked to you by Director Fury.
你最好向我道歉
I suggest you apologise.
你一直都很忙
You've been very busy.
你把小辣椒任命为首席执行官 把你的财产到处送人
You made your girl your CEO, you're giving away all your stuff.
还让你朋友穿着钢铁盔甲飞走！
You let your friend fly away with your suit.
要不是我了解状况…
Now, if I didn't know better...
我没有给他 是他抢走的
You don't know better. I didn't give it to him. He took it.
什么？是他抢走的？
Whoa, whoa, whoa. He took it?
你是钢铁侠 他就这样抢走？
You're Iron Man and he just took it?
他痛扁你一顿 抢走你的钢铁盔甲
The little brother walked in there, kicked your ass and took your suit?
这有可能吗？
Is that possible?
根据斯塔克先生的安检程序
Well, according to Mr Stark's database security guidelines,
系统可以避免未授权使用
there are redundancies to prevent unauthorised usage.
-你要我做什么？ -我们要你做什么？
-What do you want from me? -What do we want from you?
应该是你要我做什么？
What do you want from me?
你变成我得处理的问题人物
You have become a problem, a problem I have to deal with.
你可能想错了 我的世界不是绕着你运行的
Contrary to your belief, you are not the centre of my universe.
西南区有比你更大的问题
I have bigger problems than you in the southwest region to deal with.
打针吧
Hit him.
你们是要拿走我的肾脏去卖吗？
Oh, God, are you gonna steal my kidney and sell it?
可不可以别再做这些怪事
Could you please not do anything awful for five seconds?
-她刚才对我做了什么？ -我们是为了你好
-What did she just do to me? -What did we just do for you?
那是二氧化锂 能减缓你的病征
That's lithium dioxide. It's gonna take the edge off.
我们想让你回去工作
We're trying to get you back to work.
再给我两盒我就会好起来
Give me a couple of boxes of that. I'll be right as rain.
那不是解药 只能减缓病征
It's not a cure, it just abates the symptoms.
看来要治好你并不容易
Doesn't look like it's gonna be an easy fix.
相信我 我知道 我了解状况
Trust me, I know. I'm good at this stuff.
我一直在找钯元素的替代品
I've been looking for a suitable replacement for palladium.
我试过每种元素的每种组合
I've tried every combination, every permutation of every known element.
我是来告诉你 你还没全部试过
Well, I'm here to tell you, you haven't tried them all.
你有快递！
Hey, hey, hey. Special delivery.
使命必达！
Candygram.
我带了东西给你
I brought you something.
没错
Oh, yeah.
我们找到你的小鸟 兄弟！
We got you the bird, pal.
这不是我的小鸟
This is not my bird.
什么意思？这就是那只小鸟
What do you mean? That's the bird. This is the bird.
我靠很多关系才找到的
Yeah. Pulled a lot of strings to get this bird.
这是只很棒的小鸟
This is a great bird.
-而且很漂亮 -大老远从俄罗斯找来的
-It's a beautiful bird. -We got this all the way from Russia.
老兄 这不是我的小鸟
Hey, man, this not my bird.
嗯听着 就算不是你那只小鸟 这只小鸟也很漂亮
Well, listen, even if it's not the bird, I mean, this is a gorgeous bird.
别这么固执
I mean, you know, look, don't get so attached to things.
你得学会放手
Learn to let go.
等一下 杰克 那是什么？
Wait a minute. Jack, what is that?
那…那不是头盔 那是什么？
Is that... That's not a helmet. What is that?
伊万？那是什么？杰克
Ivan... What's this? Jack.
那是头盔吗？看起来不像
Is that a helmet? It doesn't look like a helmet to me.
你要怎么把头塞进去？
How... How are you supposed to get a head in there?
-杰克 你的头塞得进去吗？ -不
-Jack, could you put your head in there? -No.
试着把头塞进去 试试看 试着塞进去
Try to put your head in there. Go ahead. Try to put your head in there.
伊万 他的头塞不进去
See, Ivan? He can't put his head in there.
那不是头盔 那是一颗头 我得把一个人装进去
That's... That's not a helmet. It's a head. I need to put a guy in there.
这套钢铁盔甲要能穿 你了吗？
I need to fit a person in that suit. You understand?
-摇控钢铁士兵比较好 -摇控钢铁士兵比较好？
-Drone better. -What? Drone better?
为什么比较好？
Why is drone better? Why is drone better?
人会出错
People make problem.
相信我 摇控比较好
Trust me. Drone better.
伊万 你知道我喜欢你 我还替你弄到小鸟
Ivan, you know, I like you. I got you the bird.
你说没问题
You said, "No problem."
是你说的 你说没问题
That's what you said to me. You said, "No problem."
现在我要钢铁盔甲 政府要的是钢铁盔甲
Now I need suits. The government wants suits.
像钢铁侠一样！你了吗？
Like Iron Man. You understand?
那是大家要的！这样他们才高兴
That's what the people want. That's what's gonna make them happy.
老兄
Hey, man.
别这么固执
Don't get too attached to things.
你得学会放手
Learn to let go.
这些钢铁士兵最好能一炮而红
These drones better steal the show, Ivan.
了吗？它们最好能让我出名！
You understand? Better rock my world, Ivan.
不可思议
Unbelievable.
这样一来参议院就不会再烦我
This ought to get the Senate off my ass.
-它能用吗？ -完全能够执行任务
-It's functional? -Fully mission-capable.
很好 请汉默替它装上武器
Good. Get Hammer down here to weaponize it.
长官？
Sir?
汉默要在博览会上展示新武器
Justin Hammer's making a weapons presentation at the Expo.
我们要用这个来做开场
We'd like this to introduce it.
我不认为博览会适合…
Sir, I don't believe that the Expo...
中校 世人需要看到这玩意
Colonel, the world needs to see this fast.
-我们必须满足他们 -是的 将军 但是…
-We've got to make this happen. -Yes, General, but...
这也是个命令
It's also an order.
遵命 长官
Yes, sir.
干得好 中校 国家以你为荣
Good work, Colonel. You've made your country proud.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
你胸口的那玩意是根据未完成的科技做的
That thing in your chest is based on unfinished technology.
不 它是完成品
No, it was finished.
我把它缩小后才起了功效
It has never been particularly effective until I miniaturised it and put it in my...
不 你爸说方舟反应炉…
No. Howard said the arc reactor
只是更伟大的科技的跳板
was the stepping stone to something greater.
他当年准备展开一场能量竞争 会让所有对手望尘莫及
He was about to kick off an energy race that was gonna dwarf the arms race.
他摸索到了一种超能量的头绪
He was on to something big,
核子反应炉在相较之下…
something so big that it was gonna make the nuclear reactor
会像是一枚3A电池
look like a triple-A battery.
只有他吗？安东・万科也有参与吧？
Just him, or was Anton Vanko in on this, too?
安东・万科就像铜板的另一面
Anton Vanko is the other side of that coin.
他认为那是发大财的方法
Anton saw it as a way to get rich.
你父亲发现后就把他驱逐出境
When your father found out, he had him deported.
当老俄发现他没有用处
When the Russians found out he couldn't deliver,
就把他下放到西伯利亚
they shipped his ass off to Siberia
20年来过着酗酒愤世的生活
and he spent the next 20 years in a vodka-fuelled rage.
对小孩成长不是很好
Not quite the environment you want to raise a kid in,
你在摩纳哥遇到就是他儿子
the son you had the misfortune of crossing paths with in Monaco.
你说我没全部试过
You told me I hadn't tried everything.
什么意思？我没试过什么？
What do you mean I haven't tried everything? What haven't I tried?
他说只有你有资源和智慧…
He said that you were the only person with the means and knowledge
去完成他开始的计划
to finish what he started.
他这么说？
He said that?
他说的是你吗？
Are you that guy? Are you?
如果是你…你就能解开你的心头之谜
'Cause if you are, then you can solve the riddle of your heart.
我不知道你是怎么知道这些事
I don't know where you get your information,
但他并不是很肯定我
but he wasn't my biggest fan.
你记得你爸什么？
What do you remember about your dad?
他很冷漠 重心计
He was cold, he was calculating.
从来没说过他爱我 也从来没说过他喜欢我
He never told me he loved me. He never even told me he liked me,
对我来说很难理解的是
so it's a little tough for me to digest
你来告诉我说所有的未来都取决于我自己
when you're telling me he said the whole future was riding on me
而且他把这个责任传承给我 我不明白
and he's passing it down. I don't get that.
他最高兴的一天
You're talking about a guy whose happiest day
是把我送到寄宿学校
was when he shipped me off to boarding school.
并不是这样
That's not true.
那么很显然你比我更了解我爸
Well, then, clearly you knew my dad better than I did.
事实上没错 他是成立神盾局的成员之一
As a matter of fact, I did. He was one of the founding members of S.H.I.E.L.D.
什么？
What?
-我2点钟有约  -等等…
-I got a 2:00. -Wait, wait, wait, wait.
-这是什么？  -你可以 对吧？
-What's this? -Okay, you're good, right?
-不 我不可以 -你能解开 对吧？
-No, I'm not good. -You got this? Right? Right?
我连要解开什么都不知道
Got what? I don't even know what I'm supposed to get.
娜塔莎会继续在斯塔克工业卧底
Natasha will remain a floater at Stark with her cover intact.
-你记得考森特工吧？ -记得
-You remember Agent Coulson, right? -Yeah.
噢 托尼
And Tony,
记住 我会盯着你
remember, I got my eye on you.
我们已切断所有的通讯 不能对外联系
We've disabled all communications. No contact with the outside world.
祝好运
Good luck.
拜托
Please.
首先 我需要做体能训练 我会在实验室工作一下
First thing, I need a little bodywork. I'll put in a little time at the lab.
如果你能派手下到星巴克
If we could send one of your goon squad down to The Coffee Bean,
替我买些食物和饮料就更好
Cross Creek, for a Starbucks run, or something like that, that'd be nice.
这不是我的职责
I'm not here for that.
福瑞局长命令我…
I've been authorised by Director Fury
用任何手段让你留在这里
to use any means necessary to keep you on premises.
如果你想离开或是耍什么花招
If you attempt to leave or play any games,
我会用电晕你 然后边看《超级保姆》边看你在地上流口水
I will tase you and watch Supernanny while you drool into the carpet.
-好吗？ -我想我明白了
-Okay? -I think I got it, yeah.
享受你今晚的娱乐吧
Enjoy your evening's entertainment.
“霍华德・斯塔克所有物”
这就是它们的能量来源吗？
Think this is the power source?
少校 这不是科学实验 专心把武器装上去 好吗？
Major, this is not a scientific exercise. Let's just focus on arming it, all right?
是的 长官
Yes, sir.
好！
Oh, yes!
好！好！
Oh, yes, yes, yes.
今天是我生日吗？
Is it my birthday?
不是吧？你做了什么？
You got it. What did you do? What did you do?
-这是我想的那玩意吗？ -是的
-Is this what I think it is? -Yes, it is.
我要知道你能替我们做什么
Hammer, I want to know what you're gonna do for us.
我要替你们做什么？
What am I going to do for you?
我要先替你们的软件升级
Well, the first thing I'm gonna do for you is I'm gonna upgrade your software.
-于是 其次呢 我觉得应该…  -我说的不是这个
-And then, second, I think I should... -That's not what I'm talking about.
我说的是火力
I'm talking about firepower.
那你就找对人了
Well, you're talking to the right guy.
克拉里奇高科技半自动手枪 九毫米子弹
Claridge Hi-Tec, semi-automatic, 9mm pistol.
太差了吗？我同意
Too downtown? I agree.
M24霰弹枪 手动上膛
M24 shotgun, pump action.
每个弹匣五发子弹
Five-round magazine.
你知道什么？你又不是猎人
You know what? You're not a hunter.
我在说什么？我会把它丢掉
What am I talking about? I'm getting rid of it.
这是比利时制FN2000冲锋枪
This is the FN-2000 from Belgium.
比利时人不是只会做松饼
They do make something better than waffles.
太赞了 不过你好像不满意
It's beautiful, but I can tell this isn't disco enough for you,
所以我把它放在旁边
so I'm gonna put it right here.
这是40厘米口径榴弹枪
You're looking at a Milkor 40mm grenade launcher.
能发射催泪弹、烟雾弹 对付痞子的
Tear gas, smoke. Hippie control.
你的要求很高喔
You're tough.
让我告诉你 大小很重要
Let me tell you something. Size does matter.
不要信别人说不重要
Don't let anyone tell you different.
这是M134机枪
This is an M134 7.62 Minigun.
6根独立枪管 一枪就能让人烟消云散
Six individual barrels. The torso taker, powder maker.
士兵都戏称为电蚊香或泡泡龙
Our boys in uniform call it Uncle Gazpacho, or Puff the Magic Dragon.
好吧
Okay.
这些是顶级古巴雪茄 高希霸 蒙特克里斯托
These are the Cubans, baby. This is the Cohibas, the Montecristos.
这是响尾蛇飞弹 附装旋风炸药
This is a kinetic-kill, side-winder vehicle
具有环三次甲基三硝基胺炸药
with a secondary cyclotrimethylenetrinitramine RDX burst.
足以炸毁一座碉堡以及藏在更底下的碉堡
It's capable of busting the bunker under the bunker you just busted.
它再聪明一点就会自己写书
If it were any smarter, it would write a book.
绝对比小说《尤利西斯》更艰涩
A book that would make Ulysses look like it was written in crayon.
而且还会自己读给你听
It would read it to you.
这是我的艾菲尔铁塔
This is my Eiffel Tower.
我的拉赫曼尼诺夫第三交响曲 我的经典之作
This is my Rachmaninoff's Th ird. My Pieta.
造型优雅 美到不行
It's completely elegant. It's bafflingly beautiful.
可以把任何建筑物夷为平地
It's capable of reducing the population of any standing structure to zero.
我把它命名为“前妻”
I call it the Ex-Wife.
这是我最好的武器
That's the best I got.
你到底要不要？给我个暗示
Are we gonna do this? Give me something here.
-你就像狮身人面 我解不开你这个谜 -我要了
-You're like a sphinx. I can't read you. -I think I'll take it.
-哪一款？ -全部
-Which one? -All of it.
全部
All of it.
“方舟反应炉 万科-斯塔克”
“苏联科学家叛逃”
（开麦拉）
一切都能透过科技达成
Everything is achievable through technology.
更好的生活、健康的身体
Better living, robust health
以及人类历史上第一次…维持世界和平的可能性
and for the first time in human history, the possibility of world peace.
我是霍华德・斯塔克
I'm Howard Stark,
你在未来需要的一切都在这里
and everything you'll need for the future can be found right here.
未来城市？明日之都？未来城…
City of the Future? City of Tomorrow? City of...
我是霍华德・斯塔克
I'm Howard Stark,
你在未来需要的一切都在这里
and everything you'll need in the future can be found right here.
我想亲自为斯塔克工业…
So, from all of us at Stark lndustries, I would like to personally...
托尼 你在干嘛？那是什么？
Tony, what are you doing back there? What is that?
放回去 放回原来的地方！
Put that back. Put it back where you got it from.
你妈呢？玛莉亚？
Where's your mother? Maria?
快走…快走…
Go on. Go, go, go, go.
好了 应该可以了
All right, I think we got...
我要进来 然后…
I'll... I'll... I'll come in and...
你们在等我吗？
Are you waiting on me?
我想代表全公司让你们看…
So, from all of us at Stark lndustries, I'd like to personally show you
我的屁股
my ass.
我想…我是说…
I'd like to... I can't... This is...
都拍完了 不是吗？
I can't... We have this, don't we?
这工作太荒谬了
This is a ridiculous way...
一切都能…透过科技…达成
Everything is achievable through technology.
托尼
Tony?
你太小 现在还不懂
You're too young to understand this right now,
所以我就先替你拍下这一段
so I thought I would put it on film for you.
这一切是为你而打造
I built this for you.
有一天你会明白…
And someday you'll realise that it represents a whole lot more
这代表的不只是人类的发明 它也是我毕生的成就
than just people's inventions. It represents my life's work.
这是未来之钥
This is the key to the future.
我受到这个时代科技的限制 但有一天你会了解这一切
I'm limited by the technology of my time, but one day you'll figure this out.
到时候你就会改变世界
And when you do, you will change the world.
我最伟大的创作永远就只有…
What is and always will be my greatest creation
你
is you.
（你好 先生）
-六块钱 -我没有钱
-$6. Six. -I don't have any dough.
-用这个换 -不行 这太多了
-Here. -No, sir, that's too much.
不 没关系 拿着吧
No, it's fine. Take that.
-没事的 -不行啦 先生
-It's fine. -No, se?or.
快拿去吧 我不喜欢别人拿东西给我
Take it. Take it. I don't like people handing me things.
请你把它放在那里
If you just drop that there, that'd be great.
-你是钢铁侠吗？ -有时候是
-Are you Iron Man? -Sometimes.
我们相信你！
We believe in you.
这算非法没收私人财物
It was an illegal seizure of trademark property.
-波兹小姐？  -放轻松
-Miss Potts? -Relax.
-斯塔克先生… -在这儿
-Mr Stark... -Is here.
-他不肯…  -对 没关系
-He refuses... -I don't. It's fine.
-我只要一下子  -注意 我们的立场是
-I'll just be a second. -Listen, it's our position
斯塔克工业继续拥有…
that Stark has and continues to maintain
马克二号钢铁盔甲的产权
proprietary ownership of the Mark II platform.
当斯塔克先生宣布他是钢铁侠
When Mr Stark announced he was indeed Iron Man,
-他向美国承诺过 -不 这个钢铁外套属于我们
-he was making a promise to America. -No, the suit belongs to us.
他说过会保护我们
We trusted that he would look out for us.
-嗯 但是你没…伯特… -他很显然并没有
-Yeah, but you're not... Burt... -He obviously did not.
-现在我们发现他的秘书 -不 是的
-And now we learn that his secretary... -Yes, it does.
一个叫小辣椒波兹的女生
...a woman named Virginia "Pepper" Potts,
居然被任命为斯塔克工业首席执行官
has been appointed as CEO of Stark lndustries.
她有什么资历？
What are her qualifications?
-不 -波兹小姐
-No. -Ms Potts is doing
根本什么资历都…
nothing to manage this terrible...
-静音 -不…
-Mute. -No...
柏特…听我说
Burt... Burt... Burt, listen to me.
别跟我说我们有最好的律师
Don't tell me that we have the best patent laWyers in the country
然后说你不让我追诉下去
and then not let me pursue this.
我会把东西拿走…
I'll get this stuff out of here.
那就叫总统签署行政命令
Well, then, tell the President to sign an order.
我们在博览会上再说
We'll talk about it at the Expo.
汉默明天要举行展示会
Hammer's giving some presentation tomorrow evening.
-托尼也会去吗？ -我会去吗？
-Will Tony Stark be there? -Will I?
-不 他不会去 再见  -我很想去
-No, he will not. Bye. -I would like to be.
-有空吗？  -没有
-Got a minute? -No.
你才讲完电话 只要30秒
Come on, you just got off the phone. You're fine, 30 seconds.
29秒…28秒…
Twenty-nine. Twenty-eight.
我开车过来的时候…
I was just driving over here,
还想来道歉 但现在我不了
and I thought I was coming to basically apologise, but I'm not.
-你不是来道歉的？ -不必说你也知道
-You didn't come here to apologise? -Look, that goes without saying,
我正在努力
and I'm working on that.
但我并没有完全跟你说实话
But I haven't been entirely upfront with you,
我只想跟你和好
and I just want to try to make good.
我能把这玩意移走吗？这太扯了
Can I move this? This is crazy.
就像摩天轮一样
It's like a Ferris wheel going.
-我试着想要…  -不行
-I'm trying to get some... -No.
你知道人生有多短吗？
Do you know how short life is?
我从来没有机会表达…
And if I never got to express...
我也是最近才领悟到这一点
And by the way, this is somewhat revelatory to me.
我不在乎…我是说我在乎…
And I don't care... I mean, I care. It would be nice.
我并不期望你…
I'm not expecting you to...
听好 我只想说的是
Look, here's what I'm trying to say.
-我要说这个  -让我先阻止你说下去 好吗？
-I'm just gonna say it. -Let me stop you right here, okay?
要是你再说一次“我”…
Because if you say "I" one more time,
我就要拿东西砸你的头
I'm gonna actually hurl something at your head, I think.
我试着经营一家公司
I am trying to run a company.
-你知道这有多难吗？ -知道
-Do you have any idea what that entails? -Yes.
大家都期待你当钢铁侠 你却消失无踪
People are relying on you to be Iron Man and you've disappeared,
我只能替你灭火 被别人痛骂
and all I'm doing is putting out your fires and taking the heat for it.
我正在试着做你应该做的事
I am trying to do the job that you were meant to do.
你带了草莓给我？
Did you bring me strawberries?
你知道全世界我只对一样东西过敏吗？
Did you know that there's only one thing on Earth that I'm allergic to?
草莓…
Allergic to strawberries.
这是进步 小辣椒
This is progress, Pepper.
我就知道你和草莓有关联
I knew there was a correlation between you and this.
-我需要你… -我也需要你…
-I need you... -I need you, too.
-…马上离开 -那就我尽力想…
-...to leave now. -That's what I'm trying to...
波兹小姐？
Ms Potts?
-嗨 请进 -25分钟后起飞
-Hi, come on in. -Wheels up in 25 minutes.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-还要什么吗 老板？ -没有了
-Anything else, boss? -I'm good, Hap.
我还好…我马上就来
No, I'll be just...another minute.
我好像离了婚又失去两个小孩
I lost both the kids in the divorce.
不
No.
你融入得还好吧 娜塔莉？我是说融入斯塔克工业
Are you blending in well here, Natalie? Here at Stark Enterprises?
你叫娜塔莉 对吧？
Your name is Natalie, isn't it?
我以为你们俩不合
I thought you two didn't get along.
-并没有 -你只是不关心我了
-No. That's not so. -It's just me you don't care for.
-完全没反应？ -你人都来了
-No? Nothing? -Actually, while you're here,
就可以和娜塔莉讨论私人物件
maybe you and Natalie could discuss the matter of the personal belongings.
当然了
Absolutely.
你就是不肯闭嘴 是吧？
I'm surprised you can keep your mouth shut.
你超厉害的
Boy, you're good.
你很会装B的 你是怎么做到的？
You are mind-blowingly duplicitous. How do you do it?
你这个三面间谍
You just tear things... You're a triple impostor.
我没见过你这种人 你有什么是真的吗？
I've never seen anything like you. Is there anything real about you?
你真的会说拉丁语吗？
Do you even speak Latin?
（拉丁语）
什么意思？你刚刚说什么？
Which means? Wait. What? What did you just say?
意思是你可以自己回家或者我派人押你回去
It means you can either drive yourself home or I can have you collected.
你太厉害了！
You're good.
“未来之钥在这里”
贾维斯 请你做出数位模型
Jarvis, could you kindly Vac-U-Form a digital wire frame?
我需要一个可操作投影画面
I need a manipulatable projection.
1974年斯塔克工业博览会…
1974 Stark Expo model scan complete, sir.
（模型扫瞄完毕）
总共有几楝建筑物？
How many buildings are there?
包括比利时松饼摊位吗？
Am I to include the Belgian waffle stands?
我只是问问 秀给我看
That was rhetorical. Just show me.
这看起来像什么？有点像原子
What does that look like to you, Jarvis? Not unlike an atom.
原子核应该在这里
In which case the nucleus would be here.
把大地球仪突显出来
Highlight the unisphere.
-把走道拿掉 全都丢掉 -你想达成什么？
-Lose the footpaths. Get rid of them. -What is it you're trying to achieve, sir?
我想发现…更正
I'm discovering... Correction.
我想重新发现一个新元素
I'm rediscovering a new element, I believe.
把景观弄掉 灌木丛、树木
Lose the landscaping, the shrubbery, the trees.
停车场、出口、入口
Parking lots, exits, entrances.
利用凉亭作为架构构成质子和中子
Structure the protons and the neutrons using the pavilions as a framework.
爸
Dad.
你死了20年还要替我上课？
Dead for almost 20 years, and still taking me to school.
你发现的新元素应该能取代你在用的钯元素
The proposed element should serve as a viable replacement for palladium.
谢了 老爸
Thanks, Dad.
可惜的是 无法合成出来
Unfortunately, it is impossible to synthesise.
准备进行大翻修 伙计 是时候流些汗了
Get ready for a major remodel, fellas. We're back in hardware mode.
-听说你离开过 -是的
-I heard you broke the perimeter. -Yeah.
那是上辈子的事 你去哪里了？
That was, like, three years ago. Where you been?
-我有事 -是吗？我也是 而且成功了
-I was doing some stuff. -Yeah, well, me, too, and it worked.
我在和你们合作
Hey, I'm playing for the home team, Coulson,
替你们的男孩团体做事
you and all your Fabulous Furry Freak Brothers.
你要让我干活还是找我殖？
Now, are you gonna let me work or break my balls?
这怎么会在这里？
What's this doing here?
就是这个
That's it.
-拿给我  -你知道这是什么？
-Bring that to me. -You know what this is?
有用的东西
It's exactly what I need to make this work.
抬一下管道
Lift the coil.
快点 用力
Go, go. Put your knees into it.
很好 然后…
There you go. And...
放下去 放下去
Drop it. Drop it.
完全平衡 我很忙 你想干嘛？
Perfectly level. I'm busy. What do you want?
说再见 我被调职了
Nothing. Goodbye. I've been reassigned.
我要去新墨西哥州
Director Fury wants me in New Mexico.
-迷人仙境 -大家都这么说
-Fantastic. Land of Enchantment. -So I'm told.
-秘密任务  -差不多
-Secret stuff? -Something like that.
-祝好运  -拜
-Good luck. -Bye.
-谢了  -我们需要你
-Thanks. -We need you.
-是啊 超需要我的 -并没有
-Yeah, more than you know. -Not that much.
启动棱镜加速器
Initialising prismatic accelerator.
接近最高能量
Approaching maximum power.
很简单嘛
That was easy.
恭喜了
Congratulations, sir.
你创造了一个新元素
You have created a new element.
反应炉接受更新后的核心
Sir, the reactor has accepted the modified core.
我会开始进行测试
I will begin running diagnostics.
嘿 伊万
Hey, Ivan.
史丹议员跟我在一起
I got Senator Stern here.
我想让他看看钢铁士兵
Thought we'd swing over and look at some of the drone designs.
钢铁士兵还没准备好
The drone is not going to be ready.
你是什么意思？
Not ready? What do you mean?
我只能展示 不能示范
I can make presentation, not demonstration.
那有什么不同？
What the hell is the difference?
展示 不能飞 不能开火
Presentation. No fly. No shoot.
等等 等等 等等 等等
Well, wait, wait. Wait, wait, wait.
你能让它们做什么？这是一场军火秀
What can you make them do? I mean, this is a weapons demonstration.
-我能让它们敬礼 -我能让它们敬礼？
-I can make salute. -You can make salute?
什么意思？敬礼？
What do you mean, "make salute"?
那是什么意思 伊万？这不是我们讲好的条件吗？
What the hell does that mean, lvan? This is not what we agreed to, okay?
你答应要做钢铁盔甲 然后答应要做钢铁士兵
You promised me suits and then you promised me drones.
-老兄 一切都会好的 -这不是我要的
-Hey, man, everything will be okay. -This is not what I wanted.
他在这里 鸟人！
Hey, there he is. It's the bird man.
你开始喜欢这只鸟了 对吧？这是你的鸟吗？我被搞混了
Now you like the bird. Is that right? Is that your bird? I'm confused.
你说不是 现在却很麻吉
You said it wasn't, but now it looks like you're best of pals.
你很爱那只鸟对吧？ 把那只鸟拿走
You love that bird, don't you? You know what? Take the bird.
把他的两个枕头也拿走
Take his pillows, too. Both of them.
还有他的鞋子
And his shoes. Take his shoes.
我拿走你的东西
I took your stuff.
感觉怎样？很不爽吗？
How does that make you feel? Do you feel bad?
很好 因为我也超不爽的！
Good. 'Cause that's how I feel!
我们签了合约
We had a contract.
我救你一命
I saved your life
你给我钢铁盔甲
and you give me suits.
这是我们的条件
That was our deal.
你却没有做到
And you did not deliver.
我不知道你是天才或骗子 我不知道你是什么
I don't know if you're a genius or a fraud. I don't know what you are.
幸好从天上掉下一个礼物
Something really, really great fell into my lap.
不然你就会把我害惨了
And if it hadn't, I'd be at your mercy tonight.
现在我拥有改良版的史氏科技
Now I have a piece of Stark tech that I pimped out myself.
你那高价的的钢铁士兵
And now your overpriced paperweights
只能当我的作为示范布景的道具
are gonna look like a backdrop to my demonstration.
你懂我的意思吗？
Do you dig what I'm getting at here?
也许你还没搞清楚 我听不懂俄文！
I don't know if you know this, but I don't speak Russian!
我现在要离开
I'm gonna leave now.
我要去参加博览会了 搞不好能泡到MM
I'm gonna go to the Expo. Maybe I'll even get laid.
这些家伙是你的保母
You see these guys? They're your babysitters.
千万别惹毛他们
They are not to be trifled with.
等我回来再重新谈
When I get back, we're gonna renegotiate
合约的条件
the terms of our agreement.
你一定要做到你答应做的事
And you're gonna make good on our arrangement
要是你做不到
because if you don't,
你就会跟以前我发现你时一样
you're gonna be exactly what you were when I found you,
是个死人
a dead man.
懂了吗？
You got that?
也许你能在电视上看到我
Maybe you can watch me on TV.
老兄 能把这里打扫干净吗？晕死我了
Dummy, you, can we clean up this mess? You're killing me.
-你知道我不…  -来电了
-You know I don't... -Incoming call
未显示号码 长官
with a blocked number, sir.
我又可以接电话了 太好了
My phone privilege is reinstated. Lovely.
考森 迷人仙境如何？
Coulson. How's the Land of Enchantment?
托尼 你好吗？
Hey, Tony, how you doing?
-我加倍了转速 -什么？
-I double cycle. -You what?
你叫我加倍转速制造更多能量 很好的建议
You told me double cycle's more power. Good advice.
你这死人头听起来精神很好
You sound pretty sprightly for a dead guy.
你也是
You, too.
-追踪来电 -先生
-Trace him. -Sir.
斯塔克的家族史将被改写
Now, the true history of Stark name will be written.
贾维斯 他在哪里？
Jarvis, where is he?
进入甲骨文电话网络 美国东岸
Accessing the Oracle grid. Eastern Seaboard.
你爸在40年闲对我家族做的事
What your father did to my family over 40 years,
我会在40分钟内对你做完
I will do to you in 40 minutes.
听起来不错 咱们好好聊聊
Sounds good. Let's get together and hash it out.
三州地区
Tri-State area.
曼哈顿和邻近行政区
Manhattan and outlying boroughs.
希望你准备好了
I hope you're ready.
追踪失败
Call trace incomplete.
“捍卫和平”
-先生！ -你就这样进行测试吧
-Sir... -You want to run some tests, run them.
马上组装钢铁盔甲
And assemble the suit while you're at it. Put it together now.
-我们不确定… -我不想听到这些 贾维斯
-We are unclear as to the effects... -I don't want to hear it, Jarvis.
味道像椰子
That tastes like coconut.
还有金属
And metal.
哇 好！
Oh, wow, yeah!
我会把车停在这里
I'll keep the car down here, all right?
谢了 哈皮
Thank you, Happy.
…贾斯汀・汉默 他的展示会即将在主厅举行
...Justin Hammer. His presentation will begin shortly in the main pavilion.
好！
Yeah.
这样才对嘛 多谢光临
That's what I'm talking about. Thanks for coming.
各位先生女士 长久以来
Ladies and gentlemen, for far too long,
我们国家让英勇的士兵冒险作战
this country has had to place its brave men and women in harm's way,
后来钢铁侠出现了
but then the Iron Man arrived,
我们以为不会再失去人命
and we thought the days of losing lives were behind us.
但是他却不肯公开先进科技
Sadly, that technology was kept out of reach.
这不公平 也不对
That's not fair. That's not right.
-而且太可惜了 -天啊
-And it's just too bad. -Oh, Lord.
不过那仍是很棒的发明
Regardless, it was an impressive innovation,
成为世界各地的头条新闻
one that grabbed headlines the world over.
今天 朋友们
Well, today, my friends,
各大报社的麻烦大了
the press is faced with quite a different problem.
他们的油墨将不够用
They are about to run out of ink.
把这玩意移开
Get that out of here.
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen,
今天我将为大家介绍
today I present to you
美国军方全新的面孔
the new face of the United States military.
汉默钢铁士兵！
The Hammer drone.
陆军钢铁士兵！
Army!
海军钢铁士兵！
Navy!
空军钢铁士兵！
Air Force!
海军陆战队钢铁士兵！
Marines!
好！
Yeah!
它们比啦啦队员好太多了 我来告诉你
That's a hell of a lot better than some cheerleaders, let me tell you.
虽然这是革命性的科技
But as revolutionary as this technology is,
但是仍然需要把真正的士兵派遣到战场上
there will always be a need for man to be present in the theatre of war.
女士们先生们 我很荣幸能介绍
Ladies and gentlemen, today I am proud to present to you
第一个原型
the very first prototype
全面性威胁反应战斗盔甲装
in the Variable Threat Response Battle Suit
以及它的驾驶员-空军中校詹姆斯・罗德
and its pilot, Air Force Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes.
什么？
What?
汉默工业向美国和盟国报到…
For America and its allies, Hammer Industries is reporting for...
麻烦大了
We got trouble.
托尼 这里有平民
Tony, there are civilians present.
我是奉命行事 别在这里开打
I'm here on orders. Let's not do this right now.
向他们挥手
Give them a wave.
嘿 没事
Hey, all right. Yeah.
大家都有危险 我们得救他们
All these people are in danger. We gotta get them out of here.
现在你一定要信任我
You gotta trust me for the next five minutes.
我试过 结果在你家被打得很惨
Yeah, I tried that. I got tossed around your house, remember?
听好 我认为他和万科合作
Listen, I think he's working with Vanko.
万科还活着？
Vanko's alive?
他在哪里？
Where is he?
-什么？  -万科在哪里？
-What? -Where's Vanko?
-谁？  -告诉我
-Who? -Tell me.
你跑来干嘛 老兄？
What are you doing here, man?
“瞄准”
-是你吗？ -不是我 那不是我
-Is that you? -No, I'm not doing that. That's not me.
我动不了 我被锁死了 我被锁死了！
I can't move. I'm locked up. I'm locked up!
快走 整个系统都被他控制了
Get out of here. Go! This whole system's been compromised.
我们到外面再打吧
Let's take it outside.
“出动”
不 不！
No. No!
-贾维斯 骇进他的电脑 -遵命 长官
-Jarvis, break in. I need to own him. -Yes, sir.
托尼 我锁定目标了
Tony, Tony, I'm locked on. I have target lock.
-目标是谁？  -你！
-On what? -On you.
托尼 我在你后面！
Tony, on your six!
-发生什么事？ -软体被更改了
-What's going on? What's happening? -The software's been overridden.
什么？被更改是什么意思？
What? What do you mean it's been overridden?
-是什么意思？ -他控制了钢铁士兵
-What does that mean? -I think he slaved the drones.
不可能
That's impossible.
-打给警卫 -电话线全都被切断 长官
-Call the guards. -All the phones are down, sir.
那就打给他们的手机
Well, then call their... Call their cells.
手机也没有讯号
Their cell phones are not working, either, sir.
我们被档在主机外面
He's locked us out of the mainframe.
谁把你们挡在主机外面？
Who's locked you out of the mainframe?
借光 借光 走开 走开
Please, please, go away. Go away.
-我可以搞定 -是吗？
-I've got this handled. -Have you now?
当然了
Yes, I do.
钢铁侠不来就不会发生这种事
In fact, if your guy hadn't showed up, this wouldn't be happening.
拜托你走开 谢谢你
So please, now go away. Thank you.
我们得把那两个臭婆娘弄走
Listen, we got to get these bitches out of here.
什么？
What?
告诉我是谁在搞鬼
You tell me who's behind this.
-谁在搞鬼？ -伊万 伊万万科
-Who's behind this? -Ivan. Ivan Vanko.
-他在哪里？ -他在我的公司
-Where is he? -He's at my facility.
-请帮我接纽约警局总部 -不 不 不！
-I need NYPD, please. -No, no, no!
-指挥中心 -不 不 亲爱的
-Command Central. -No, no, honey.
-不！别打给警方 -好 马上 马上
-Don't call the authorities. -Okay. Right away. Right away.
让开！让开！
Step aside. Step aside.
告诉我你知道的一切
Tell me everything you know. Go.
-贾维斯 情况如何？ -无法远端重新开机
-How are we doing, Jarvis? -Remote reboot unsuccessful.
从这里
This way.
发生什么事？
Nobody's answering the phone. What's going on?
上车 载我到汉默工业
Get in the car. Take me to Hammer Industries.
-我才不要载你 -好吧 你要我开车吗？
-I'm not taking you anywhere. -Fine. You want me to drive?
不 我来开 上车
No, I'm driving. Get in the car.
“失去连线”
干得好 小鬼
Nice work, kid.
-多具钢铁士兵在追你 -我们离博览会愈远愈好
-You got multiples coming in on you. -Let's get this away from the Expo.
到了以后我要你守住外面
When we arrive, I need you to watch the perimeter.
我要进去消灭目标
I'm gonna enter the facility and take down the target.
-眼睛看前面！  -知道了啦
-Watch the road. -I got it. I got it.
“失去连线”
听好
Listen, listen.
一群钢铁士兵刚脱队 它们飞回博览会
A pack just peeled off. They're headed back to the Expo.
收到
Got it.
我正逼近你！
I'm closing on you.
准备向你开火！托尼 小心！
Ordnance coming in hot, Tony. Watch it.
-待在车上 -我才不要待在车上
-Stay in the car. -I'm not staying in the car.
我叫你待在车上
I said, stay in the car.
你穿的是什么？
What are you wearing?
我不能让你一个人进去
Look, I'm not letting you go in there alone.
你想帮忙？别让车子熄火
You want to help? Keep the car running.
好吧
Okay.
“外人侵入”
你们不能进来！
You can't come in here.
稳住
Hold on. Hey!
“出动”
每组钢铁士兵
Each set of drones is communicating
-用自己的语言沟通 -挑一组 阻止它们
-in its own unique language. -Well, choose one and focus on that.
你们试过俄语了吗？你们怎么不试试俄语？
Have you tried Russian? Why don't you try Russian?
注意 我们已经侵入了网格W
Attention. We have intrusion on Grid W.
收到 我们已经开始了
We got it. We're on our way.
我摇倒他了！
I got him!
-洛德 你还在锁定我吗？  -对
-Rhodey, you still locked on? -Yeah.
穿好雨衣 我们就要洗澡了
Drop your socks and grab your Crocs. We're about to get wet on this ride.
等等…等等…
Wait, wait, wait!
他离开了！
He's gone.
抱歉 我得减少敌人数量
I'm sorry, buddy. Had to thin out the herd.
你在哪里？
What's your 20?
-你在干嘛？ -替洛德的战斗装重新开机
-What are you doing? -I'm rebooting Rhodey's suit.
托尼！
Tony!
“准许进入”
完成重新开机
Reboot complete.
你的好麻吉回来了
You got your best friend back.
-多谢了 罗曼诺夫特工 -你的全新能量板很棒
-Thank you very much, Agent Romanoff. -Well done with the new chest piece.
我发现输出的能量更强了 你的生命迹象也很正常
I am reading significantly higher output and your vitals all look promising.
是啊 我暂时死不了 谢了
Yes, for the moment, I'm not dying. Thank you.
什么意思？你本来快死了？
What do you mean you're not dying? Did you just say you're dying?
是你吗？不 我没死
Is that you? No, I'm not.
-我不会死了 -发生什么事？
-Not any more. -What's going on?
我本来要告诉你
I was going to tell you. I didn't want to alarm you.
你要告诉我？你本来要死吗？
You were gonna tell me? You really were dying?
-你没给我机会说 -你为什么不告诉我？
-You didn't let me. -Why didn't you tell me that?
上次煎蛋卷的时候本来要说
I was gonna make you an omelette and tell you.
你们等度蜜月再聊吧 敌人来袭 托尼
Hey, hey. Save it for the honeymoon. You got incoming, Tony.
看来它们盯上你了
Looks like the fight's coming to you.
-太棒了 小辣椒？ -你现在没事了？
-Great. Pepper? -Are you okay now?
我没事 别生气
I am fine. Don't be mad.
-我正式道歉… -我很生气
-I will formally apologise... -I am mad!
先等我闪避攻击再说
...when I'm not fending off a Hammeroid attack.
-好吧 -我们本来是在威尼斯的
-Fine. -We could have been in Venice.
噢 拜托
Oh, please.
洛德！
Rhodes?
快醒醒 我需要你
Snap out of it, buddy. I need you.
它们攻来了 快醒过来
They're coming. Come on, let's roll. Get up.
你可以把钢铁盔甲拿回去
Oh, man. You can have your suit back.
你没事吧？
You okay?
没事 谢了
Yeah, thanks.
-托尼 听好 很抱歉 -别道歉
-Tony, look, I'm sorry, okay? -Don't be.
我应该更信任你
No. I should have trusted you more.
是我害你的 算了吧
I'm the one who put you in this position. Forget it.
对 是你的错 我只想说声抱歉
No. It's your fault. I just wanted to say I'm sorry.
谢了 我也只想听你这么说 伙伴
Thank you. That's all I wanted to hear. Partner.
它们正在追来 有什么对策？
They're coming in hot, any second. What's the play?
我们要到制高点
Well, we want to take the high ground, okay?
把最猛的大炮带到山脊
So let's put the biggest gun up on that ridge.
收到
Got you.
-那你要去哪里？ -你要去哪里？
-Where do you want to be? -Where are you going?
-你在说什么？ -我是说我啦
-What're you talking about? -I meant me.
你是有一支大炮 但不是最猛的
You have a big gun. You are not the big gun.
-托尼 别嫉妒我 -不 是低调
-Tony, don't be jealous. -No. It's subtle,
-全身挂满了东东 -是的
-all the bells and whistles. -Yeah.
-我这才叫狠角色  -好吧
-It's called being a badass. -Fine.
你到制高点 我把它们引来
All right. You go up top. I'll draw them in.
别待在这里 太危险了
Don't stay down here. This is the worst place to be.
你有地方去 那我呢？
Okay, you got a spot. Where's mine?
这里是杀戮区 托尼 待在这里必死无疑
It's the kill box, Tony. Okay? This is where you go to die.
-看到没？  -有 好样的
-See that? -Yeah, yeah, nice.
洛德…
Rhodey?
趴下来！
Get down.
下次你应该先用这招
Wow. I think you should lead with that next time.
抱歉 老板 这招只能用一次 这是一次性的
Yeah. Sorry, boss. I can only use it once. It's a one-off.
我5分钟前就跟你说了
I told you that five minutes ago.
你要抓的就是他
That's your guy here.
-说什么？ -先生 你被捕了
-Excuse me? -You're being placed under arrest.
-你在开玩笑吧？  -手放在背后
-Are you kidding me? -Hands behind your back, sir.
我想帮忙
I'm trying to help here.
我明白 我知道你的诡计 你想把一切都归罪于我吗？
I get it. I see what you're doing. You're trying to pin this on me, huh?
好样的
That's good. That's good.
你开始像首席执行官一样思考 铲除竞争对手
You're starting to think like a CEO, taking out the competition.
我喜欢 你以为你让我惹上大麻烦？
I like that. You think you're making a problem for me?
我才要让你惹上大麻烦
I'm gonna make a problem for you.
我们很快会再见面
I'm gonna be seeing you again real soon.
他们赶来以后 你应该请他们守在
When they get here, I think you should station them
东南和西方两个出口
at the south, east and both west exits.
我们关闭了七号线地铁
We shut down the 7 train in and out of Willets Point already.
派公车载人接驳没关闭的地铁
Well, have city buses there to ferry people to operating lines.
好 你要一起来吗？
Yeah. Are you coming with us?
-不 我要等到大家都疏散了 -好吧
-No, I'm gonna stay till the park is clear. -Okay.
小心 一个钢铁士兵来袭
Heads up. You got one more drone incoming.
这一个看起来不太一样
This one looks different.
能量指数特别高
The repulsor signature is significantly higher.
回来真好
Good to be back.
情况不妙
This ain't gonna be good.
我要用特别的武器对付他
I got something special for this guy.
让我用“前妻”把他打爆
I'm gonna bust his bunker with the Ex-Wife.
用什么？
With the what?
-汉默的武器？ -对
-Hammer tech? -Yeah.
让我来吧
I got this.
罗德 我有个点子
Rhodes. I got an idea.
-你想当英雄吗？ -什么？
-You want to be a hero? -What?
我需要一个助手 举起手
I could really use a sidekick. Put your hand up.
-这就是你的点子？ -对
-This is your idea? -Yep.
我准备好了 来吧…
I'm ready. I'm ready. Go, go, go!
发射！
Take it.
你输了
You lose.
钢铁士兵都会自爆 我们得赶快闪人
All these drones are rigged to blow. We gotta get out of here, man.
小辣椒？
Pepper?
天啊 我受不了了
Oh, my God! I can't take this any more.
-你受不了？  -我受不了了
-You can't? -I can't take this.
-看着我 -我的身体 字面意思
-Look at me. -My body, literally,
承受不了这种压力
cannot handle the stress.
我永远不知道你会不会死或是毁了整家公司
I never know if you're gonna kill yourself or wreck the whole company.
我想我做得不错
I think I did okay.
老娘不干了 我要辞职
I quit. I'm resigning.
就是这样
That's it.
你说什么？你不干了？
What did you just say? You're done?
这倒是很令人惊讶 不 这不奇怪 我了解
That's surprising. No, it's not surprising. I get it.
-你不必找藉口 -我…我…我并没有找藉口
-You don't have to make any excuses. -I'm... I'm... I'm not making any excuses.
你是真的在找藉口
You actually were just making excuses.
-其实你无需这样 -不 我没有找藉口
-But you don't have to. -No, I wasn't making an excuse.
-实际上我是对的 -听着 嘿嘿
-I'm actually very justified. -Listen. Hey, hey.
-你应该得到更好的待遇 -呃…
-You deserve better. -Well...
你一直把我照顾得好好的
You've taken such good care of me.
我每次有困难 你都会救我
I've been in a tough spot, but you got me through it, so...
对吗？
Right?
谢谢你
Thank you.
-谢谢你的了解 -咱们得讨论该怎么善后
-Thank you for understanding. -Yeah, yeah. Let's talk clean-up.
-我会处理职位转交的细节 会平息的  -怎么应付媒体？
-I'll handle the transition. It'll be smooth. -Okay. What about the press?
你才当了一个礼拜首席执行官
Because you only had the job for a week. That's gonna seem...
-感觉像是当了一百年 -我知道
-Well, with you it's like dog years. -I know.
或像当总统…
I mean, it's like the Presidency...
超怪的
Weird.
-并不会呀  -还不错 对吧？
-No, it's not weird. -It's okay, right?
-对啊 -再一次
-Yeah. -Run that by me again.
我觉得超怪的
I think it was weird.
你们亲密得好像两只在抢葡萄的海豹
You guys look like two seals fighting over a grape.
-实际上 我刚辞职了 -是的 那么我们不…
-I had just quit, actually. -Yeah, so we're not...
你不必解释 我全都听见了
You don't have to do that. I heard the whole thing.
-你最好给我闪人 -我先来的 去找自己的屋顶
-You should get lost. -I was here first. Get a roof.
-我以为你没冷笑话可说了 -那是最后一个
-I thought you were out of one-liners. -That's the last one.
-你刚才打得很猛 -谢了 你也是
-You kicked ass back there, by the way. -Thank you. You, too.
我的车被炸烂了
Listen, my car got taken out in the explosion,
我要先借用你的钢铁盔甲
so I'm gonna have to hang on to your suit for a minute, okay?
不行 想都别想
Not okay. Not okay with that.
我不是在问你
It wasn't a question.
如果我不接受 你要怎么辞职？
How are you gonna resign if I don't accept?
“超人联盟初步报告”
我不想让你看那份报告
I don't think I want you looking at that.
我不确定这跟你有关
I'm not sure it pertains to you any more.
至于这份报告 是罗曼诺夫特工对你的评估
Now this, on the other hand, is Agent Romanoff's assessment of you.
你自己看吧
Read it.
“性格分析 斯塔克常做出冲动的行为”
"Personality overview. Mr Stark displays compulsive behaviour."
那只是上礼拜的事
In my own defence, that was last week.
“有自我毁灭的倾向” 当时我快死了
"Prone to self-destructive tendencies." I was dying.
拜托 我们不都是这样吗？
I mean, please. And aren't we all?
“典型的自恋狂？”
"Textbook narcissism"?
我同意
Agreed.
读到这里…
Okay, here it is.
“超人联盟招募评估 钢铁侠…可以”
"Recruitment assessment for Avenger Initiative. Iron Man? Yes."
-我得考虑看看 -继续读下去
-I gotta think about it. -Read on.
托尼・斯塔克…
"Tony Stark not...
不被推荐？
"Not recommended"?
这没有道理
That doesn't make any sense.
你们怎么能接受另一个我却不接受真正的我？
How can you approve me but not approve me?
我有全新的心脏
I got a new ticker.
也打算好好对待小辣椒
I'm trying to do right by Pepper.
我们的关系很稳定
I'm in a stable-ish relationship.
值此之际 让我们相信的是
Which leads us to believe at this juncture
你目前只能担任顾问
we'd only like to use you as a consultant.
你们请不起我
You can't afford me.
不过我愿意用我的约聘费…
Then again, I will waive my customary retainer
请你们帮我一个小忙
in exchange for a small favour.
华盛顿要颁奖给我和洛德 我们需要一位颁奖贵宾
Rhodey and I are being honoured in Washington and we need a presenter.
我会想想办法
I'll see what I can do.
今天我很荣幸来到这里颁发这种卓越的奖项给
It is my honour to be here today to present these distinguished awards
詹姆斯・罗德中校以及托尼・斯塔克先生
to Lieutenant Colonel James Rhodes and Mr Tony Stark,
无庸置疑 他是个国宝
who is, of course, a national treasure.
谢谢 中校
Thank you, Lieutenant Colonel,
感谢你优异的表现
for such an exceptionally distinguished performance.
-这是你应得的 -谢谢你
-You deserve this. -Thank you, sir.
斯塔克先生
Mr Stark.
感谢你这么优秀的表现
Thank you for such an exceptionally distinguished performance.
这是你应得的
You deserve this.
抱歉
Oh, sorry.
怎么会有人这么讨人厌？
Funny how annoying a little prick can be, isn't it?
咱们来合照吧
Let's get a photo.
（新墨西哥州迷人仙境）
长官…我们找到了
Sir, we've found it.